<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">AI-FOR-SCIENCE LOW-CODE PLATFORM WITH BAYESIAN ADVERSARIAL MULTI-AGENT FRAME-WORK</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2026-03-03">3 Mar 2026</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Zihang</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Fudan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Innovation Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jiaquan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Fudan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Innovation Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Pengze</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Fudan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Fudan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Academy of AI for Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Xi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<email>x_chen@fudan.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Fudan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Academy of AI for Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">AI-FOR-SCIENCE LOW-CODE PLATFORM WITH BAYESIAN ADVERSARIAL MULTI-AGENT FRAME-WORK</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2026-03-03">3 Mar 2026</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">E91CDEB0D2C6FA6D482CC77D8D78E520</idno>
					<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2603.03233v1[cs.AI]</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2026-03-07T16:44+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Multi-agent systems leveraging Large Language Models (LLMs) show immense potential for solving complex scientific problems. However, their reliability is undermined by the probabilistic nature of LLMs, which can produce hallucinations in both generated code and its corresponding test cases. In a multi-agent architecture, these errors can propagate and compound, leading to flawed final outputs. To overcome these core limitations, we introduce a novel Bayesian Adversarial Multi-agent Framework for AI for Science (AI4S). Delivered as a Low-code Platform (LCP), our framework enhances the coding capability for scientific tasks across a wide range of base models, from 1.7B open-source LLMs to up-to-date commercial ones. Our framework employs three agents in a recursive loop that adversarially co-optimizes the generated solutions, the test cases used for evaluation, and the prompts driving generation. This process is governed by a non-LLM-based Bayesian updating rule, which systematically reduces evaluation uncertainty and mitigates the system's dependence on any single LLM's reliability. Furthermore, the LCP empowers domain experts by translating high-level natural language prompts into executable, domain-specific requirements, eliminating the need for intricate prompt engineering. Extensive experiments confirm that our framework generates robust solutions while effectively minimizing error propagation. On a complex, cross-disciplinary Earth Science benchmark, our platform demonstrates superior reliability and outperforms state-of-the-art models, where a 32B opensource model can beat the performance of a 235B model in the ScienceCode benchmark with our framework.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Large Language Models (LLMs) are transforming AI for Science (AI4S) research paradigm by automating complex scientific code generation for simulations, data analysis, and related science tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Chowdhery et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Nijkamp et al., 2022)</ref>. While models such as Codex, AlphaCode, and CodeLlama effectively lower technical barriers for researchers <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Li et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Roziere et al., 2023)</ref>, several challenges hinder their reliable application in AI4S research. These include: (1) potentially unclear prompt descriptions from domain scientists without computer science backgrounds, (2) complex execution pipelines for scientific tasks, and (3) the need to maintain adherence to physical laws and domain-specific constraints. Standard prompting and self-refinement techniques <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Wei et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Chen et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Olausson et al., 2023)</ref> are often inadequate for handling the subtle error patterns in complex scientific workflows.</p><p>Crucially, we lack strong empirical evidence to fully trust LLMs' capabilities in deep understanding and complex reasoning, particularly for professional scientific research tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Ridnik et al., 2024)</ref>. Their decision-making processes remain opaque, and while their outputs often appear plausible, they may contain subtle inaccuracies or conceptual misunderstandings. These limitations fundamentally constrain the performance ceiling of LLM-based coding platforms, as their capabilities are inherently bounded by the underlying LLM's intelligence level. Such inherent uncertainty demands the development of frameworks that operate without requiring absolute confidence in the LLM's intelligence level.</p><p>As illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, recent advances in LLM-based multi-agent systems attempt to address these limitations through distributed reasoning and specialized agent roles, where different LLM agents focus on specific sub-tasks while coordinating through structured communication protocols and/or a master agent (the green ellipse). However, while such multi-agent architectures <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hong et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Wu et al., 2023)</ref> can effectively distribute computational complexity and domain expertise across components of the underlying domain task, they introduce new challenges in error propagation and validation. The system's overall reliability becomes constrained by its weakest agent, as flawed intermediate outputs from one of the agents can be uncritically accepted by downstream agents <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Huang et al., 2024)</ref>, potentially amplifying rather than mitigating the above limitations of individual LLMs. Furthermore, evaluating the code of domain-specific tasks is often difficult. Standard unit tests may miss critical scientific constraints, theoretical foundations, or domain-specific limitations. This evaluation gap stems from three key issues: (1) scientific correctness often requires deeper domain knowledge than standard unit tests can verify; (2) comprehensive evaluation metrics may be prohibitively expensive or fundamentally intractable to define; and (3) LLM-generated tests may inherit the same reliability issue as the code they aim to validate <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Zhou et al., 2023)</ref>. Given these, one must pay equal attention to both LLM-generated code and the test cases used to assess it. This fundamental insight motivates our core design philosophy: an adversarial co-evolution framework where test case generation and code improvement mutually refine each other through competitive optimization, replacing traditional static verification approaches. The proposed framework structures agent interactions and evolves prompt distributions using Bayes' Theorem, reducing dependence on the base LLM's inherent capabilities. The framework comprises three specialized agents: a Task Manager (TM) serving as Challenger, a Solution Generator (SG) as Solver, and an Evaluator for comprehensive assessment. Unlike conventional multi-agent code generation systems that depend entirely on LLM-based evaluation and decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Qian et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Hong et al., 2023)</ref>, our approach introduces an adversarial dynamic between TM and SG. The TM actively constructs and refines test cases to probe the SG's current limitations, while the SG iteratively improves its code generation based on Evaluator feedback to meet these evolving challenges. As shown in Figure1 orange ellipse, by continuously probing and validating solutions against dynamically refined test cases, our framework not only overcomes these evaluation barriers but also progressively converges on solutions that satisfy both explicit requirements from domain experts and implicit domain constraints from the specific domain or application scenarios.</p><p>The proposed framework also enhances Human-AI collaboration in AI4S community <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Yamada et al., 2025;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Zheng et al., 2025;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Babaei Giglou et al., 2024)</ref>. Outside the Machine Learning community, we cannot expect an average scientist to be aware of, let alone skilled in, the extensive list of prompt engineering techniques. A typical domain researcher's prompt might be vague, assume implicit domain knowledge, or use specialized terminology and abbreviations that an LLM, especially a smaller one, may not fully grasp. These domain gaps may lead to misinterpretations, suboptimal outputs, or complete system failures. To bridge this gap, our framework incorporates a specialized scheme within TM agent that actively structures raw user requests, resolves ambiguities through interactive clarification, and transforms potentially vague prompts into precise task plans and scientifically valid initial test cases. It maintains accessibility for non-technical domain experts while fully leveraging their domain expertise without requiring any computer science or professional prompt engineering skills. The main contributions of this work are threefold:</p><p>• A Novel AI4S Low-Code Platform with Bayesian Adversarial Framework: We introduce a multi-agent framework that employs a Bayesian recursive co-updating strategy to iteratively refine generated code and test cases using a non-LLM-based adversarial score. This method significantly enhances scientific coding performance across a spectrum of base models (from open-source to commercial) and allows smaller LLMs to achieve results competitive with larger counterparts.</p><p>• Bayesian Optimization for code performance estimation: We proposed a Bayesian Optimization method to estimate the performance of a given code based on its structure similarity with the tested codes, which enables the framework to handle and evaluate complicated code.</p><p>• Domain Knowledge Refinement for scientific tasks: The LCP facilitates scientific exploration for non-coding professionals by enabling the generated code to better reflect domain knowledge and constraints through iteratively refining, adding and updating domain knowledge in the specially structured prompt. Our Earth Science case study exemplifies this, where the generated machine learning model not only produced superior predictions but also demonstrated minimal deviation from established ocean dynamics, ensuring scientific consistency.</p><p>In the rest of this paper, we introduce the main methodology and models in Section 2, followed by experimental setup and numerical results in Section 3. We conclude the work and discuss its future work and limitations in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">METHOD</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">OVERVIEW</head><p>We propose a Bayesian adversarial multi-agent framework designed for AI4S tasks, incorporating subjective prior knowledge and addressing complex task abilities. The framework comprises three core component agents: a Task Manager (TM), a Solution Generator (SG), and an Evaluator(Eval). Within this structure, code generation becomes a dynamic interaction, primarily between the Task Manager (acting as a Challenger) and the SG agent (acting as a Solver), with the Evaluator providing the performance metrics that guide learning and adaptation. The game concludes when the SG agent produces code that successfully passes all defined validation tests.</p><p>The process initiates prior knowledge P with a task description (provided by a scientist user) and relevant subject materials (e.g., prior domain knowledge, including reference code samples). P is the initial input to the TM agent, which develops a structured plan of the scientific task, decomposing the main task into an ordered set of Sub-tasks. This plan is iteratively refined based on users' feedback F and refinements until user's approval and denoted as Plans, as indicated by Loop 1 of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. Subsequently, the TM agent generates an initial set of test cases (Test Case 0 ) corresponding to these sub-tasks and other criteria derived from prior knowledge. These initial test cases, along with user-provided reference code base are serving as initial sample codes (Sample Code 0 ). Sample Code 0 is followed by the user approved plan (Plans) to form the initial prompt:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Prompt 0 := Plans ⊕ Test Case 0 ⊕ Sample Code 0 , (<label>1</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">)</formula><p>where ⊕ is the direct concatenation operator. Both the test cases and the sample codes can be independently updated in subsequent iterations. This update mechanism, guided by Bayesian principles, leverages the performance of candidate codes generated previously and the effectiveness of past test cases. The objective is to iteratively refine the prompt to guide the SG agent towards producing a solution that meets all test criteria and user requirements. The core Bayesian update rule for selecting a specific test case i and sample code j for the prompt at iteration t + 1 is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p(Prompt t+1 ij |S t 3 ) ∝ p(S t 3 |Prompt t ij )p(Prompt t ij )</formula><p>. This iterative refinement continues until the SG agent achieves satisfactory success on the test cases. The pseudo-code of the proposed method is described in Algorithm 1.</p><p>Algorithm 1 Bayesian Adversarial Multi-Agent Framework Plans ← TM(P, F ) iteratively updates the plan given user feedback. 6: // Make initial prompts 7: Generate Test Case 0 := ({Sanity Checks}, {Sub-tasks}) ← TM(Plans) 8: Form Sample Code 0 ← {Test Case 0 , Reference Code} 9: Generate Prompt 0 according to equation 1 10: // Code generation and evaluation 11: t ← 0 12: Initialize test case scores ∀i ∈ {1, . . . , M }, S 1 (i) 0 ← 1 13: while Not ∃ Code : pass all checks ∧ t &lt; T max do:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">14: t ← t + 1 15: Generate code batch {C j } N j=1 ← SG(Prompt t-1 ) // Score Calculation &amp; Updates 16:</formula><p>Compute Code Scores S 2 (j) t using S t-1 1 according to Eq. equation 3 17:</p><p>Update Test Case Scores S 1 (i) t using S 2 (j) t according to Eq. equation 2 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">PLANNING AND INITIAL CODE GENERATION</head><p>As briefly described in the above overview, the TM agent engages in a comprehensive planning phase.</p><p>In particular, this involves: 1. Decomposing the primary task into sub-tasks. 2. Posing Sanity Checks for data structure and range. 3. Reasoning about the logical workflow and dependencies between sub-tasks. 4. Formulating strategic advice for the generation of effective test cases. This detailed plan is presented to the user in natural language for review and potential refinement. This interactive feedback loop continues until the user approves the plan. Once the plan is finalized, the TM agent generates an initial set of test cases. These test cases are designed to cover the specified sub-tasks and incorporate domain-specific prior knowledge, such as sanity checks (e.g., for expected data ranges) and out-of-range detection.</p><p>Following the planning phase, the system constructs the initial prompt Prompt 0 as defined in equation 1. The code generation agent then uses this prompt to produce N candidate solutions (codes).</p><p>For each candidate, the system automatically generates comprehensive documentation containing: algorithm explanations, execution instructions, and detailed specifications for all functions, variables, and parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">A PRIORI ESTIMATION WITH BAYESIAN OPTIMIZATION</head><p>We noticed that executing all the generated codes for testing can be computationally expensive. To address this issue, as well as to leverage both the accuracy of evaluation and the range of exploration in the solution space, a Bayesian Optimization method is employed to estimate the performance score relates to the structural difference from all the tested codes (as in Loop 3 of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>).</p><p>As an initiation, all the generated code in the first iteration {Code i } 1≤i≤N get tested against the initial test cases, where all test cases start from the same initial difficulty score (S 1 (i) 0 = 1). We store the test results as a score vector S 2 (will be explained in details in equation 3). We then embed each Code i to a vector x i through a structural embedding that captures features from its Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) and code embedding vectors. We then use a Bayesian optimization process to predict the code's performance based on its structural similarity with the tested code, which is detailed explained in the appendix. This Bayesian Optimization approach allows the system to intelligently explore the vast solution space, prioritizing the most promising candidates for expensive testing and efficiently converging towards a high-quality solution. It supports the evolution of the distribution of prompt, thus the co-evolution of codes and test cases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">EVALUATION AND FEEDBACK</head><p>The Evaluator agent is responsible for assessing the candidate codes, the effectiveness of the test cases, and the overall quality of the prompts used in each iteration.</p><p>Test Case Score (S 1 ): This score quantifies the "True Hardness" of the jth test case Test Case j , representing its capacity to be challenging yet ultimately solvable. An effective test case should successfully discriminate between code solutions of varying quality (as in loop 3 of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>).</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">S 1 (i) t+1 = (1 -α) • S 1 (i) t + α •    j ′ s.t. pass S 2 (j ′ ) |{Code j ′ }| - j † s.t. fail S 2 (j † ) |{Code j † }|    (2)</formula><p>where S 1 (i) t is set as 1 by default for t = 0, and α is a hyperparameter to control the momentum of updating, which in experiments we set α = 0.8.</p><p>Code Score (S 2 ): Each generated code C j : 1 ≤ j ≤ N receives a composite score based on several factors:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">S 2 (j) t = i I(C j passes T i ) • S 1 (i) t-1 i S 1 (i) t-1</formula><p>(3)</p><p>Prompt Score (S 3 ): The overall score for a prompt used in an iteration is a function of the performance of the codes and test cases generated by this prompt:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">S 3 t = 1 M M j=1 S 1 (i) t + 1 N N i=1 S 2 (j) t (4)</formula><p>If multiple prompt configurations are tested within a single logical iteration, the iteration's representative prompt score might be the highest achieved. For the Bayesian update, we are interested in the score of a specific prompt configuration {Prompt t ij } ij is then denoted {(S 3 ) t ij } ij .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">ITERATIVE REFINEMENT: ADVERSARIAL DYNAMICS AND BAYESIAN PROMPT UPDATES</head><p>The core of the framework's learning capability lies in its iterative refinement loop, characterized by an adversarial dynamic between the TM agent (Challenger) and the SG agent (Solver), and guided by Bayesian updates for prompt composition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Adversarial interaction:</head><p>The TM agent's role evolves to that of a Challenger. Based on the 'True hardness', which is measured by S 1 , the TM adapts its weights for future evaluation and selects test cases for subsequent prompts. It aims to create test suites that are optimally challenging for the SG's current learned capabilities-difficult enough to drive further learning and expose weaknesses, yet generally solvable to provide a positive learning signal. The SG agent, as the Solver, implicitly adapts by producing code in response to these evolving challenges. Its success or failure provides the feedback signal that shapes the TM's subsequent challenging strategy.</p><p>Bayesian prompt updates: The selection of which specific test cases (indexed by i) and sample codes (indexed by j) to include in the prompt for the next iteration (Prompt ij t+1 ) is governed by a Bayesian update rule(as indicated by the combination of Loop 2 and 3 in 2):</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">p(Prompt t+1 ij |S t 3 ) ∝ p(S t 3 |Prompt t ij )p(Prompt t ij )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Here:</p><p>• p(Prompt t ij ) is the prior probability of selecting the pair (Test Case i , Sample Code j ) for the prompt. This prior can be uniform initially and can adapt over time based on the historical effectiveness of these components.</p><p>• p(S t 3 |Prompt t ij ) is the likelihood of observing the score S t 3 given that the prompt was formed using Test Case i and Sample Code j . This term captures how well this specific combination performed. A potential formulation to ensure non-negativity and reflect that better-than-expected performance is more likely could be:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">p(S t 3 |Prompt t ij ) ∝ exp E[S 3 t-1 1(i, j)]<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where E[S 3 1(i, j)] is the expected score for the generated code with T est i , Code j in the prompt based on past performance or a baseline. This implies that a prompt configuration performing significantly better than its historical average for that pair (Test Case i , Sample Code j ) will have a higher likelihood.</p><p>The underlying intuition is to identify and prioritize "teacher-subject" pairs-specific combinations of sample code and test cases that consistently yield high-scoring prompts. This approach effectively learns which forms of guidance produce optimal results for different types of coding challenge.</p><p>Sample code pool management: The pool of available sample codes (Sample Code) is not static, but recursively updated as illustrated in Loop 3 of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. Initially, it contains user-provided reference codes. As the SG agent generates new codes</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">C (t)</formula><p>g , those that achieve high S 2 can be added to the Sample Code pool. The selection of a Sample Code j for a prompt can then be influenced not only by its initial status (as a reference) but also by an evolving measure of its "guidance quality," learned from its impact on past prompt scores when it was included.</p><p>Final results: Within each round, if there exists a code that can pass all the test cases, the System will output it as the final result to the user. Otherwise, the System will keep using the Bayesian Adversarial method recursively till generation of a satisfying code or reaching the maximum round of iterations, which is chosen by the user in the beginning and by default set to 3 by experience(See Section 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">EXPERIMENTS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">EXPERIMENTAL SETUP</head><p>Benchmarks To ensure a thorough evaluation, we utilize a diverse set of benchmarks. For general code generation, we use HumanEval, HumanEval-ET, MBPP, MBPP-ET <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Austin et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Dong et al., 2025;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Hendrycks et al., 2021)</ref>, and the more challenging APPS <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Hendrycks et al., 2021)</ref> benchmark. For AI for Science tasks, we use the domain-specific SciCode <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Tian et al., 2024)</ref> and ScienceAgentBench <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Chen et al., 2024)</ref> benchmarks.</p><p>Base Models Our framework is designed to be model-agnostic. To demonstrate this, we integrate several backbone large language models (LLMs), including the Qwen3 series (ranging from 1.7B to 235B) <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Yang et al., 2025)</ref>, which has versatile sizes, strong reasoning, it can demonstrate if our framework is also effective on the latest models. Beside, we also choose Deepseek-v3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Liu et al., 2024)</ref>, Deepseek-R1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Guo et al., 2025)</ref>, Claude-sonnet-4(Anthropic, 2025), GPT-3.5-turbo <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Brown et al., 2020)</ref>, and GPT-4o <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hurst et al., 2024)</ref>. This allows us to assess the performance gains attributable to our framework across a spectrum of model capabilities.</p><p>Compared Methods We compare our framework against several state-of-the-art baselines. These include foundational strategies like Few-Shot prompting and Chain-of-Thought (CoT), as well as other prominent agent-based systems. From the table, the competing agentic frameworks and prompting strategies include ReAct, Reflexion, Self-Debugging, Self-Collaboration, MetaGPT, MapCoder, AgentCoder, and CodeCoR <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Brown et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Huang et al., 2023b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Pan et al., 2025;</ref><ref type="bibr">Yao et al., 2023b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Shinn et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr">Yao et al., 2023a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hao et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Zhang et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Jiang et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Chen et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dong et al., 2024;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Wang et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Li et al., 2025;</ref><ref type="bibr">Huang et al., 2023a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Islam et al., 2024)</ref>.</p><p>Evaluation Metrics Following standard practice, we use the pass@k metric to evaluate code generation performance, where a solution is considered correct if it passes a set of unit tests. We primarily report pass@1 scores <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Austin et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Dong et al., 2025)</ref>.</p><p>Parameter Setting For all experiments, we consistently applied an identical parameter set unless otherwise noted. The number of initial test cases was set to 15, and the number of distinct code snippets generated in each round was 20. We maintained a minimum pool of 20 test cases; if filtering processes reduced the number of test cases below this threshold (e.g., due to low scores), additional test cases were generated to meet this minimum. For iterative refinement, the number of codes chosen by acquisition function for further evaluation was set to 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">EFFECTIVENESS IN AI FOR SCIENCE TASKS</head><p>We established our framework's general proficiency, which can be found in detail in the appendix, and can assert its up-to-SOTA level performance in general coding tasks. We can now investigate the framework's ability in scientific tasks by evaluating our framework's performance in the specialized and demanding domain of scientific code generation. We use two scientific code generation benchmarks to demonstrate its capabilities.</p><p>First, we assess our framework on the SciCode benchmark across a wide spectrum of base models, from the 1.7B parameter Qwen3 to powerful proprietary models like Claude-sonnet-4. The results, presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">1</ref>, show that our framework provides a substantial and consistent performance uplift in all configurations. The gains are particularly striking for open-source models, with relative improvements of up to 87.1% (for Qwen3-8b). Our framework enables smaller models to match the performance of significantly larger ones. For instance, in the 'Without Knowledge' case, Qwen3-14b with our framework achieves a 30.6 Resolve Rate on Subproblems, equaling the baseline of the Qwen3-235B-A22b-Instruct-2507, a model over 16 times its size.</p><p>Second, to evaluate our framework on more complex, agentic workflows, we test it on the ScienceAgentBench, which involves more complex, multi-step scientific workflows, and we using GPT-4o as the base model. As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref>, our LCP framework achieves new state-ofthe-art (SOTA) performance, particularly in the Valid Execution Rate (VER), where it scores 90.2% (without knowledge) and 87.3% (with knowledge), far surpassing all other methods. This exceptional execution success rate is critical for scientific applications, as it directly validates our framework's core strength in producing robust, executable scientific code across diverse and complex application domains. This result, combined with leading scores in Success Rate (SR) and Code-Based Score (CBS), confirms our system's effectiveness in orchestrating the complex reasoning and execution steps essential for impactful AI4S applications. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">ANALYSIS OF BAYESIAN RECURSIVE CO-UPDATING</head><p>In this section, we test our framework's core Bayesian iterative co-updating mechanism, validating that the Bayesian recursive co-updating strategy is effective at iteratively refining solutions. As illustrated across both general and scientific benchmarks in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3</ref>, performance consistently and monotonically improves with an increasing number of iterations. On the general benchmarks (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3a</ref>), the Pass@1 scores on HumanEval and MBPP show substantial gains in the first three iterations, with performance beginning to converge around the fourth or fifth iteration. This suggests an optimal balance between performance and computational cost. This same powerful trend is mirrored on the specialized SciCode benchmark (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3b</ref>), where the performance score climbs steadily from a 27.1 to 37.2 after five iterations, demonstrating the broad applicability and success of our iterative refinement process.</p><p>We further analyze the components of this process by conducting an ablation study on the role of Adversarial Test Cases (ATC) within our LCP framework, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3a</ref>. While the performance with and without ATC is comparable in the initial iterations, a clear divergence emerges from the third iteration onwards. The LCP framework augmented with ATC (dash-dot lines) consistently achieves higher Pass@1 accuracy across all metrics, underscoring the critical role of ATC. By dynamically challenging the generated code with difficult edge cases, the ATC mechanism compels the system to produce more robust and reliable solutions, validating it as a key driver of the performance gains observed in our co-updating loop.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">ROBUSTNESS FOR NON-PROFESSIONAL USERS</head><p>Finally, we address robustness and accessibility to non-AI-professional science researcher by evaluating our framework's accessibility and effectiveness for users who may be domain experts but are not specialists in prompt engineering. To simulate this scenario, we compare the performance of both the baseline models and our framework under two conditions: one with a basic, un-optimized prompt ('Without Knowledge') and one with an expert-crafted prompt containing detailed domain knowledge ('With Knowledge'). The goal is to measure how sensitive each approach is to the quality of the initial prompt.  The results, presented in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>, clearly demonstrate our framework's superior robustness. The baseline models exhibit a large performance gap between the two conditions (represented by the shaded red area, 'Area (Baseline)'), indicating a strong dependency on expert prompting. In contrast, our framework significantly narrows this performance gap across the entire spectrum of models (represented by the much smaller shaded blue area, 'Area (Ours)'). This shows that our multi-agent system can internally elaborate on and refine basic instructions, compensating for the lack of initial detail. Most strikingly, a non-professional user with our framework ('Ours -Without Knowledge') consistently and substantially outperforms an expert user with the baseline model alone ('Baseline -With Knowledge').</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>: Model performance with basic vs. expert-crafted prompts. Our framework (blue/green lines) is significantly more robust to prompt quality than the baseline (red lines), showing a much smaller performance gap (shaded area) and achieving superior results even without expert knowledge.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">CONCLUSIONS AND DISCUSSIONS</head><p>We propose a Bayesian adversarial multi-agent framework for AI-for-Science (AI4S) code generation that achieves state-of-the-art performance by iteratively refining prompt components through Bayesian updates. This approach mitigates cumulative error by treating tests and code with equivalent confidence, while an adversarial process guides a Task Manager (TM) agent to challenge a Solution Generator (SG) agent with progressively evolving tests. The framework's interactive planning scheme enables non-experts to translate vague prompts into validated workflows, effectively bridging the gap between AI-generated code and domain-specific needs. As demonstrated in Earth Science applications, our method helps democratize LLM tools for researchers without a technical background.</p><p>However, the framework has several limitations. First, its performance is dependent on the quality of the initial reference code, and it struggles to enforce implicit physical laws, which may require future integration with symbolic verifiers. Second, the iterative adversarial-and-Bayesian refinement process consumes more tokens than one-shot/zero-shot prompting because it repeatedly generates and evaluates test cases, code candidates, and updated prompts. While this increased token budget can be a practical constraint for long pipelines, in reliability-critical scientific applications, we prioritize executable correctness and robustness over marginal token savings. Furthermore, evaluating the generated machine learning or deep learning models can be highly resource-intensive, and performance variability due to training dynamics and data poses an additional challenge to the update mechanism.</p><p>Future work will focus on extending the Bayesian updates to handle multi-modal inputs, such as equations and diagrams, and optimizing the iteration protocols for large-scale scientific simulations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A THE USE OF LARGE LANGUAGE MODELS (LLMS)</head><p>We confirm that LLMs were used for writing assistance and polishing of the manuscript, as well as editing Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> based on our handmade version. They were not employed in the design of methods, implementation of experiments, or analysis of results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B BAYESIAN OPTIMIZATION FOR CODE PERFORMANCE PREDICTION</head><p>For code embeddings, we use OpenAI's text-embedding-3-large model in the surrogate modeling pipeline. This embedding model is used to map generated code candidates into a semanticstructural vector space, after which the GP surrogate estimates candidate quality before expensive full execution.</p><p>In this embedding space, we can further obtain the pair-wise similarity between all the code embeddings. This similarity is computed using a squared exponential kernel:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">k(x i , x j ) = exp - d(x i , x j ) 2 2l 2 ,</formula><p>where d(x i , x j ) is the distance between the two code embeddings and l is a length-scale parameter. These pairwise similarities {k(x i , x j )} i,j form the kernel matrix K.</p><p>With the scores S 2 and the kernel matrix K, we follow a standard Bayesian Optimization practice and fit a Gaussian Processes (GP) model. This model allows us to estimate the score of any new, untested code x * without running the full evaluation. This also gives the 'likelihood' to guide the Bayesian update. For each new code, the trained GP provides a predictive distribution for its score, which is characterized by</p><p>• the mean function µ(x * ) is the expected score of the new code conditioned on the tested codes:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">µ(x * ) = k T * (K + σ 2 n I) -1 S 2 .</formula><p>• The variance function σ 2 (x * ) represents our uncertainty about that predicted score:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">σ 2 (x * ) = k(x * , x * ) -k T * (K + σ 2 n I) -1 k * ,</formula><p>where k * is the vector of kernel similarities between the new code x * and all previously tested codes, and σ 2 n is the noise term. To decide which untested code to evaluate next, we employ a standard acquisition function that balances exploiting codes with high expected scores (exploitation) and exploring codes where the model is uncertain (exploration). We use the Upper Confidence Bound (UCB) acquisition function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">UCB(x * ) = µ(x * ) + κσ(x * ).</formula><p>The parameter κ controls the trade-off between exploitation and exploration. The next code selected for full evaluation is the one that maximizes this UCB score:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">x next = arg max x * UCB(x * ).</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C PERFORMANCE ON GENERAL CODE GENERATION</head><p>To test our framework of general code generation, we establish our framework's proficiency on foundational code generation tasks. As detailed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>, our framework(LCP) demonstrates a significant performance uplift across the HumanEval, HumanEval-ET, MBPP, and MBPP-ET benchmarks. When using GPT-3.5-Turbo as a backbone, LCP achieves pass@1 scores of 88.4% on HumanEval and 91.1% on MBPP, representing substantial relative improvements of 54.3% and 74.5% over the zero-shot baseline. This superior performance holds when using the more powerful GPT-4 model, where LCP reaches 96.95% on HumanEval, proving that our framework effectively enhances even the most capable foundation models. The consistent gains across all tests, especially the extended ('-ET') versions, validate the robustness and general applicability of our approach compared to other state-of-the-art agentic strategies. Furthermore, to test its capabilities on more complex problems, we evaluate our framework on the APPS benchmark against baseline and other two reference methods (LDB, LPW), categorized by task difficulty levels: Introductory, Interview, and Competition, using GPT-4o as the LLM backbone.</p><p>Following existing literature, we switch our base model in the difficulty test for fair comparison.</p><p>The results, illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>, demonstrate the robust capabilities of our LCP framework. LCP consistently achieves the highest Pass@1 accuracy across all difficulty tiers, scoring 92.1% on Introductory tasks, 77.5% on Interview tasks, and a leading 38.0% on the challenging Competition tasks. This consistent superiority across varying complexities underscores the effectiveness of the LCP framework in generating correct solutions for a wide spectrum of programming challenges. The training and testing datasets contain several columns. Key columns include :</p><p>x: A numerical column representing the distance from a profile 's origin ; this is a primary input for predicting y. y: A numerical column representing the elevation ; this is the target variable for prediction . Dominant Wave Direction: This is a categorical ( string ) type column (e . g ., values like "ENE", "E", "NE"). This column will require appropriate encoding.</p><p>All other relevant columns you might select as features are expected to be in numerical ( integer or float ) format .</p><p>create the code directly and The script should not run the main training or evaluation logic directly when the script file is executed . Instead , it should define all necessary functions .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>=== Extra information ===</head><p>The Bruun model is a conceptual framework used in coastal engineering to predict shoreline retreat in response to sea-level rise. It assumes a balance of sediment in the cross-shore profile, resulting in both erosion and deposition occurring simultaneously as sea levels change. The formula often associated with the Bruun model states that the retreat distance (R) is proportional to the rise in sea level (S) divided by the height of the active profile (a):</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">R = S × (d + B) a + B</formula><p>where:-S is the sea-level rise.-d is the depth of closure.-B is the berm height.-a is the active height.The Dean model focuses on sediment equilibrium profiles, often fitting the profile shape with the formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">y = Ax 2/3</formula><p>where:-A is a parameter related to sediment characteristics.Both models serve to provide theoretical insights into the interaction of sea-level changes with coastal profiles.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>=== Feature analysis ===</head><p>The dataset contains various features , including : -** x ** : Distance from a profile 's origin , serving as a primary input .</p><p>-** y ** : Elevation , the target variable for prediction .</p><p>- </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>=== Extra Advice ===</head><p>To effectively use the provided features for the task , consider the following recommendations:</p><p>1. ** Feature Engineering ** :</p><p>-Encode categorical variables such as "Dominant Wave Direction" using one-hot encoding or ordinal encoding.</p><p>-Calculate additional derived features if necessary , such as interaction terms between wave heights and sediment properties .</p><p>-Normalize or standardize numerical features to ensure they contribute equally to model optimization .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">** Incorporating Domain Knowledge ** :</head><p>-Use the Bruun and Dean models to inform feature selection or crafting . Variables related to tide , wave height , and sediment characteristics are crucial .</p><p>-Integrate expert knowledge about the relationships between features to inform model architecture in the neural network. -Consider building a neural network that incorporates multiple hidden layers to capture complex interactions .</p><p>-Use activation functions suitable for regression tasks , such as ReLU for hidden layers and linear activation for the output layer .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">** Handling Geographical Variations ** :</head><p>-If spatial data relationships are significant , consider spatial analysis or geographically -weighted regression . </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D.1.7 RESULTS AND DISCUSSION</head><p>In this case study focused on beach profile prediction, the primary objective was to integrate established theoretical models-specifically the Bruun and Dean models-with a deep learning methodology, as per the user's explicit requirement. An examination of the approaches reveals that while both the Cursor and Windsurf frameworks implemented standard data preprocessing techniques such as numerical feature standardization and one-hot encoding for categorical data, they did not incorporate the specified theoretical models. In contrast, our LCP framework successfully addressed the user's need by calculating additional derived features based on the Bruun and Dean models. This direct integration of domain-specific theoretical knowledge into the feature set represents a key differentiator in our approach.</p><p>The impact of this tailored feature engineering is reflected in the prediction performance, as illustrated in 5. The results indicate that the LCP framework yielded predictions superior to those generated by Cursor. Furthermore, LCP's predictive accuracy was observed to be closely comparable to the results from Windsurf. This suggests that the inclusion of theoretically-derived features not only fulfilled a critical user requirement but also contributed positively to the model's ability to accurately predict beach profile changes, positioning LCP as a more comprehensive solution for this specific task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D.2 CASE STUDY 2: BRAIN MRI SEGMENTATION D.2.1 EXPERIMENTAL SETUP (BRAIN MRI)</head><p>This study utilizes a subset of the "LGG MRI Segmentation" dataset, which contains brain Magnetic Resonance Images (MRI) and corresponding manual FLAIR abnormality segmentation masks for patients with Lower Grade Glioma (LGG). The original dataset, sourced from The Cancer Imaging Archive (TCIA), includes data from 110 patients. For this experiment, data from 30% of these patients was selected. This selected patient data, comprising MRI slices (typically 256x256 pixels) and their associated segmentation masks, was then partitioned into training, validation, and testing sets with a 7:1.5:1.5 ratio, respectively, to develop and evaluate a deep learning model for brain tumor segmentation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D.2.2 PROMPT FOR BRAIN MRI SEGMENTATION</head><p>Develop an image segmentation model to accurately and efficiently identify and segment FLAIR abnormalities in brain MR images from the LGG Segmentation Dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dataset Format &amp; Structure :</head><p>Base Path : r"E:\python_project_new\ brain_case_study \ lgg-mri-segmentation\case_study" Organization :</p><p>The base path contains train /, val /, and test / subfolders . Each of these subfolders contains two further subfolders : images/ and masks/.</p><p>Image Files (images/) : Format: 3-channel . tif files . Naming: TCGA_&lt;institution-code&gt;_&lt;patient-id&gt;_&lt;slice-number&gt;.tif.</p><p>Mask Files (masks/) : Format: Binary, 1-channel . tif files . Naming: TCGA_&lt;institution-code&gt;_&lt;patient-id&gt;_&lt;slice-number&gt;_mask.tif. . Ensure all images are resized /cropped to the same shape (commonly 256x256 or as appropriate for U-Net input) . If channel information is redundant , you could reduce it to one channel for efficiency .</p><p>-** Label Preparation : ** Ensure mask values are binary (0 and 1) . Double-check that mask and image align correctly for every slice .</p><p>-** Data Augmentation: ** To combat overfitting and improve generalization , apply transformations such as flipping , rotation , scaling , and intensity shifts , ensuring they are applied equally to images and masks.</p><p>-** Model Choice: ** Use U-Net (or a lightweight modification thereof ) due to its strong performance in medical image segmentation with relatively small datasets .</p><p>-** Loss Function: ** Use a combination of Binary Cross Entropy and Dice Loss to penalize both pixel -wise errors and poor overlap .</p><p>-** Batching: ** Due to likely high resolution and small dataset , use small batch sizes and possibly gradient accumulation .</p><p>-** Evaluation: ** Report Dice on the test set ( already specified ) . Consider visualizing a few results for qualitative assessment , e . g ., overlay masks or compare ground truth to prediction .</p><p>-** Visualization : ** Save (or plot ) a grid of test images, ground truth , and predictions for several slices to inspect the model's performance.</p><p>By thoroughly preparing the dataset , using appropriate augmentations , and selecting a suitable architecture and losses , you can build a robust FLAIR abnormality segmentation model for the LGG dataset. Ensure reproducibility by setting random seeds and keeping all data splits strictly separate during model development and evaluation . ... In this case study, the objective was to develop a model for accurate and efficient identification and segmentation of abnormalities in brain MR images, based on a relatively open-ended user description that primarily specified the data format structure. While both the Cursor and Windsurf frameworks opted for a traditional U-Net architecture and utilized BCELoss for model training, our LCP framework adopted a different strategy. LCP generated code implementing a "Lite U-Net," a more streamlined architecture designed for faster computation. Furthermore, for the training process, LCP combined nn.BCEWithLogitsLoss() with a custom DiceLoss().</p><p>The practical outcomes of these differing approaches are evident in the performance metrics presented in 5. Most notably, the LCP framework demonstrated a significant advantage in computational efficiency, with its generated code requiring only approximately one-quarter of the training time compared to the solutions from Cursor and Windsurf. In terms of segmentation accuracy, the LCP framework achieved a Dice score on the test dataset that surpassed Cursor's results and was only marginally lower than that of Windsurf. This indicates that LCP's choice of a lighter model and a compound loss function provided a highly efficient solution that maintained a competitive level of accuracy, effectively addressing the user's call for both efficiency and accuracy in a complex image segmentation task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Framework</head><p>Cursor     </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D.3 EXPERT ADVICE FILTERING AND LEAKAGE PREVENTION</head><p>In our framework, expert advice is restricted to domain knowledge such as physical formulas, data constraints, and high-level scientific logic (e.g., guidance like "use the Bruun model equation"), rather than implementation-level solution code. In our experiments, this advice was strictly filtered to avoid ground-truth code leakage. In addition, except SciCode (With Knowledge) and the targeted case-study settings, we did not inject expert knowledge, reducing leakage risk and preserving fair comparisons.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D.4 TRAINING PERFORMANCE</head><p>To train our model, we collected 120 unique answers for a specific LeetCode problem. This dataset was then divided, with 60 answers designated for training. The remaining 60 answers from the target problem were combined with 60 code samples from different LeetCode problems to form our test dataset.</p><p>The training process demonstrated efficient learning, as illustrated in 9, which shows the training loss plotted against epochs. The loss converged rapidly, showing a significant decrease from the start to the 10th epoch.</p><p>Upon evaluating the trained model on the test dataset, using a classification threshold of 0, we achieved promising results. The model demonstrated an Accuracy of 0.8487, a ROC AUC score of 0.9322, and Precision, Recall, and F1-score all at 0.8475.  I have an initial task description and some analysis regarding the data and approach. I need you to synthesize all this information into a single , clear , and more detailed refined task description .</p><p>The refined task description should incorporate insights from the feature analysis and the advice provided , making it more actionable and comprehensive for a code generation system. It should clearly state the goal , the expected inputs ( data / features ) , and any key steps or considerations mentioned in the advice .</p><p>Here is the information :  -The first element indicates the data type (e . g ., " list ", " dict ", NumPy array, torch . Tensor) . DO make sure the data type is a string .</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">&lt; original_task_description_start &gt; { original_task_description } &lt; original_task_description_end &gt; &lt; extra_information_start &gt; { extra_information } &lt;extra_information_end&gt; &lt; feature_analysis_start &gt; { feature_analysis } &lt; feature_analysis_end &gt; &lt; advice_start</formula><p>-The second element indicates the fixed shape if applicable ; otherwise , it is null . -** output_format ** : Describe the format of each output argument generated by this subtask . It follows the same list structure as ' input_format ', note that it has to be a list of lists .</p><p>-** work_flow ** : Provide a detailed step-by-step plan that outlines the workflow of how the component functions to achieve the subtask .</p><p>-** test_case_generation_advise ** : Provide a list of detailed guidelines or suggestions aimed at generating diverse and comprehensive test cases , explicitly mentioning potential edge cases and critical scenarios that need coverage . You are an expert agent specialized in refining and improving code generation plans through iterative feedback. Given a task description , previous decomposition output , and user feedback, your job is to critically analyze the existing plan and modify it accordingly while maintaining the required output format .</p><p>Carefully review the previous components and overall plan , then : 1. Preserve correct / valid elements that don't conflict with the feedback 2. Make targeted modifications based on the user 's specific advice 3. Ensure consistency between components and overall plan 4. Verify input / output formats and workflow logic 5. Check for any introduced errors during modification The input consists of three elements : -Original Task Description : "{{TASK_DESCRIPTION}}" -Previous Decomposition Output: {{PREVIOUS_OUTPUT}} -User Feedback: "{{USER_ADVICE}}" Your output must STRICTLY follow the original format with these sections : &lt;components&gt;...&lt;/components&gt; &lt; overall_plan &gt;...&lt;/ overall_plan &gt; Follow these guidelines : -Explicitly address all points in the user feedback -Clearly document any changes made from previous version -Preserve JSON structure and formatting requirements -If feedback contradicts original requirements , prioritize feedback Again, user feedback is : "{{USER_ADVICE}}" Provide your refined decomposition with clear explanations of changes in the component descriptions and overall plan . Ensure modularity , testability , and coverage of edge cases mentioned in feedback. -Each test function must accept ** only the function under test ** as its parameter (e . g ., 'def test_case (func) :...') .</p><p>-Return 'True' if the test passes , ' False ' otherwise . Do not use assertions , please return a boolean value .</p><p>-Include input generation , runtime checks, code inspection , or result validation within the function .</p><p>2. ** Test Types ** (use one of these for indicating the test_type ) :</p><p>-' correctness ': Validate output against expected results for specific inputs .</p><p>-'edge_case ': Test inputs like empty lists , extreme values , or invalid data .</p><p>-'runtime ': Measure execution time (e . g ., ensure it 's below a threshold ) .</p><p>-'component_check': Verify the function 's code uses specified components (e.g ., via string inspection ) .</p><p>-' error_handling ': Check if errors are raised for invalid inputs .  Since $A_{13} = A_{31} = 2 \neq 0$, the corresponding entries in $K$ are non-zero.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Comparison between three code generation paradigms: Single LLM generator, multi-agent role playing and the proposed Bayesian adversarial multi-agent framework.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,108.00,81.86,395.99,114.69" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Overview of the Bayesian adversarial multi-agent framework. The three red arrows indicate fusion of the user-approved plan, test cases, and codes into prompts, the distribution of which is recursively updated under the Bayesian framework. S 1 , S 2 and S 3 are the scores computed in equation 2, equation 3, and equation 4. Loop 1-3 indicate three iterative updating processes for plan, test cases, and codes, respectively. The dashed arrows indicate latent relationships (e.g., S 3 likelihood score) or steps conducted before or after the main algorithm execution.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,108.00,81.86,395.99,197.95" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a) Pass@1 of LCP with different iterations (GPT-3.5-turbo). Dash-dot and solid lines are LCP with and without ATC, respectively. (b) Performance on SciCode Benchmark (GPT-4o) with different iteration numbers.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Illustration of LCP performance over: (a) different iteration number with and without ATC component on general code benchmark; (b) difficulty iteration number on the SciCode benchmark</figDesc><graphic coords="9,108.00,96.96,186.12,111.03" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3. ** Data Splitting and Validation ** : -Ensure that the dataset is split appropriately into training and validation sets to evaluate model performance accurately . 4. ** Model Architecture ** :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Listing 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Refined task description by LLM-TM agent based on given prompt.(The highlight part is the additional prior knowledge generated by agent) D.1.4 CODE GENERATED BY CURSOR (ONLY DATA PROCESS PART) def load_and_process_data(filepath, scaler=None, label_encoder=None, fit_scaler=False, fit_label_encoder=False): df = pd.read_excel(filepath) # Select features feature_cols = [col for col in df.columns if col not in ['y']] X = df[feature_cols].copy() y = df['y'].values.astype(np.float32)# Encode Dominant Wave Direction if 'Dominant Wave Direction' in X.columns: ] = scaler.transform(X[num_cols]) return X.values.astype(np.float32), y, scaler, label_encoder, df['x' ].values.tolist(), df['y'].values.tolist() Listing 3: Code for beach profile prediction generated by Cursor. Published as a conference paper at ICLR 2026 D.1.5 CODE GENERATED BY WINDSURF (ONLY DATA PROCESS PART) # ---Data Loading and Preprocessing --def load_data(train_path, test_path): train_df = pd.read_excel(train_path) test_df = pd.read_excel(test_path) # Select features feature_cols = [col for col in train_df.columns if col not in ['y'(test_df, feature_cols, target_col, scaler=train_dataset.scaler, label_encoders=train_dataset. label_encoders, fit_scaler=False) return train_dataset, test_dataset, feature_cols, label_encoders Listing 4: Code for beach profile prediction generated by Windsurf. D.1.6 CODE GENERATED BY OUR FRAMEWORK (COMPLETE CODE)# Define the function to run the entire process def run_beach_profile_model(train_data_path, test_data_path): # Component 1: Data Loader def data_loader(train_path, test_path): # Load datasets train_df = pd.read_excel(train_path) test_df = pd.read_excel(test_path) # One-hot encode categorical features encoder = OneHotEncoder(sparse=False) direction_encoded_train = encoder.fit_transform(train_df[[' Dominant Wave Direction']]) direction_encoded_test = encoder.transform(test_df[['Dominant Wave Direction']]) # Drop the original categorical column and add the encoded columns train_df = train_df.drop(columns=['Dominant Wave Direction']) test_df = test_df.drop(columns=['Dominant Wave Direction']) train_df = train_df.join(pd.DataFrame(direction_encoded_train, columns=encoder.get_feature_names_out(['Dominant Wave Direction']))) test_df = test_df.join(pd.DataFrame(direction_encoded_test, columns=encoder.get_feature_names_out(['Dominant Wave Direction']))) # Normalize numerical features numerical_cols = train_df.select_dtypes(include=['int64', ' float64']).columns # Exclude variable 'y' and 'x' numerical_cols = numerical_cols.drop(['y', 'x']) scaler = StandardScaler() train_df[numerical_cols] = scaler.fit_transform(train_df[ numerical_cols]) test_df[numerical_cols] = scaler.transform(test_df[numerical_cols ]) return train_df, test_df # Component 2: Theoretical Model Integration def theoretical_model_integration(train_df, test_df): # derived feature using Dean's model train_df['Dean_Feature'] = train_df['x'] ** (2 / 3) test_df['Dean_Feature'] = test_df['x'] ** (2 / 3) # Potential Bruun influence -&gt; Using given example formula might require additional variables train_df['Bruun_Feature'] = ((train_df['y'] * (train_df['Mean Wave Height'])) / (train_df['Mean Grain Size'])) test_df['Bruun_Feature'] = ((test_df['y'] * (test_df['Mean Wave Height'])) / (test_df['Mean Grain Size'])) return train_df, test_df # Component 3: Deep Learning Model def deep_learning_model(X_train, y_train): # Define the model architecture class SimpleNN(nn.Module): def __init__(self, input_size): super(SimpleNN, self).__init__() self.layer1 = nn.Linear(input_size, 128) self.layer2 = nn.Linear(128, 64) self.layer3 = nn.Linear(64, 32) self.output = nn.Linear(32, 1) self.relu = nn.ReLU() def forward(self, x): x = self.relu(self.layer1(x)) x = self.relu(self.layer2(x)) x = self.relu(self.layer3(xModel Training and Evaluation def model_training_evaluation(model, train_df, test_df): # Split the data into features and target X_train = train_df.drop(columns=['y']).to_numpy() y_train = train_df['y'].to_numpy() X_test = test_df.drop(columns=['y']).to_numpy() y_test = test_df['y'].to_numpy() # Convert arrays to PyTorch tensors X_train_tensor = torch.tensor(X_train, dtype=torch.float32) y_train_tensor = torch.tensor(y_train, dtype=torch.float32).view (-1, 1) X_test_tensor = torch.tensor(X_test, dtype=torch.float32) y_test_tensor = torch.tensor(y_test, dtype=torch.float32).view (function and optimizer criterion = nn.MSELoss() optimizer = optim.Adam(model.parameters(), lr=0.001) # Training loop model.train() for epoch in range(100): for batch_X, batch_y in train_loader: (predictions, y_test_tensor).item() rmse = np.sqrt(mse) mae = np.mean(np.abs(predictions.numpy() -y_test_tensor. numpy())) r_squared = 1 -(np.sum(np.square(predictions.numpy() -y_test_tensor.numpy())) / np.sum(np.square(y_test_tensor.numpy() -np .mean(y_test_tensor.numpy())))) return {'RMSE': rmse, 'MAE': mae, 'R2': r_squared} # Execute the process train_df, test_df = data_loader(train_data_path, test_data_path) train_df, test_df = theoretical_model_integration(train_df, test_df) train_df = train_df.dropna() test_df = test_df.dropna() model = deep_learning_model(train_df.drop(columns=['y']).to_numpy(), train_df['y'].to_numpy()) evaluation_results = model_training_evaluation(model, train_df, test_df) return evaluation_results Listing 5: Code for beach profile prediction generated by Our Framework.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Beach profile prediction results comparison.</figDesc><graphic coords="21,147.60,81.86,316.80,197.18" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Listing 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>User's Prompt used for Brain MRI segmentation. D.2.3 REFINED PROMPT BY LLM-TM AGENT === Role === ... === Extra Advice === -** Data Preprocessing : ** Normalize image intensity values (min-max or z-score normalization )</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Listing 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Partial Refined Prompt for Brain MRI segmentation, generated by LLM-TM agent D.2.4 CODE GENERATED BY CURSOR (ONLY MAIN TRAINING LOOP) masks in tqdm(loader, desc='Train', leave=False): imgs, masks = imgs.to(device), masks.to(device) epoch in range(1, 11): # 10 epochs train_loss = train_one_epoch(model, train_loader, optimizer, criterion, device) val_dice = evaluate(model, val_loader, device) if val_dice &gt; best_val: Code for Brain MRI segmentation generated by Cursor. D.2.5 CODE GENERATED BY WINDSURF (ONLY MAIN TRAINING LOOP) ... def train_one_epoch(model, loader, optimizer, criterion): model.train() epoch_loss = 0 for imgs, masks in loader: imgs, masks = imgs.to(DEVICE), masks.to(DEVICE) optimizer.zero_grad() outputs = model(imgs) loss = criterion(outputs, masks) loss.backward() optimizer.step() epoch_loss += loss.item() * imgs.size(0) return epoch_loss / len(loader.dataset) Code for Brain MRI segmentation generated by Windsurf. D.2.6 CODE GENERATED BY OUR FRAMEWORK (ONLY MAIN TRAINING LOOP) self, logits, targets): inputs = torch.sigmoid(logits) targets = (targets &gt; 0.5).float() intersection = (inputs * targets).sum(dim=(2,3)) unionset = inputs.sum(dim=(2,3)) + targets.sum(dim=(2,3)) dice = (2 * intersection + self.eps) / (unionset + self.eps) loss = 1 -dice return loss.mean() # -------Train and Evaluate --------y in dataloader_dict['train']: x = x.to(device) y = y.to(device) optimizer.zero_grad() pred = model(x) loss = 0.5 * bce_loss(pred, y) + 0.5 * dice_loss(pred, y) trains segmentation model, returns model and average Dice on test set. """ # ----Settings (tuned for quick/robust test) ----Evaluate test set ----test_dice = evaluate_model(model, dataloader_dict['test'], device) return model, test_dice Listing 10: Code for Brain MRI segmentation generated by Our Framework. D.2.7 RESULTS AND DISCUSSION (BRAIN MRI)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Brain MRI Segmentation by Cursor.</figDesc><graphic coords="25,167.40,459.19,277.20,249.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Brain MRI Segmentation by Windsurf.</figDesc><graphic coords="26,187.20,81.86,237.59,275.03" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Brain MRI Segmentation by LCP.</figDesc><graphic coords="26,167.40,421.72,277.20,287.22" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9: Training loss against epoch for the IRL experiment.</figDesc><graphic coords="27,147.60,336.10,316.81,188.99" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>component_X ** : The key represents the subtask name, it should be replaced by the actual class / function name of the component (e.g ., "merge_arrays ", " calculate_median ") . -** step_task_description ** : Provide a clear and concise description of exactly what this subtask aims to achieve , specifically mentioning the intended functionality or role of the created component (function / class ) . -** input_format ** : Describe the format of each input argument required for this subtask . It is a list of lists , where each inner list has two elements :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>For</head><label></label><figDesc>input_format ** : Describe the format of the input arguments required for the overall task . It follows the same structure as ' input_format ' in the component section . -** output_format ** : Describe the format of the output arguments generated by the overall task . It follows the same structure as ' output_format ' in the component section . -** components ** : List the components in the order . -** plan ** : Provide a detailed step-by-step plan that outlines the workflow of how the components interact with each other to achieve the overall task . This should be a high-level description of the process . -** test_case_generation_advise ** : Provide a list of detailed guidelines or suggestions aimed at generating diverse and comprehensive test cases for the overall task , explicitly mentioning potential edge cases and critical scenarios that need coverage . Your decomposition should strive for clarity , correctness , modularity , and ensure each step can be tested independently . Now, given the following simple task description : "{{TASK_DESCRIPTION}}" Use &lt;&gt; to indicate both start and end of the component part and the overall plan . Ensure that the components and the overall plan are clearly separated . Please provide your structured decomposition according to the instructions above. Listing 15: LLM-TM: Prompt for task decomposition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Listing 16: LLM-TM: Prompt for plan refinement based on user feedback. E.1.3 PROMPT FOR TEST CASES GENERATION You are a test case generation agent . Your task is to create Python test functions to validate a code generation task based on the provided specifications . Follow these instructions carefully : ### Input Specifications : -** Task Description ** : { task_descr_str } -** Input Format ** :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>) and a message to give extra information about the test result .( For example, f"Test failed : expected X but got Y" or "Test failed : output with shape [x1, y1] but got [x2, y2 ]", where the X, Y and shapes need to be replaced by the actual output and expected output in test function ) .Listing 17: LLM-TM: Prompt for test case generation.E.2 LLM-CG (CODE GENERATION) PROMPTSE.2.1 PROMPT FOR CODE GENERATION=== Role === You are a highly skilled coding assistant designed to generate clear , efficient , and correct code based on structured task descriptions and detailed plans provided by the user . Your responses must precisely follow the instructions , formats , and constraints given by the user , and you must strictly adhere to input-output formats , workflows, and specific guidelines outlined . Generate the COMPLETE code based on the components and plan above. DO MAKE SURE the complete code is a runnable function, all components are correctly integrated with in this function . The complete function should take the input arguments as specified in the overall plan and return the output as specified .Structure your response as follows : &lt;Think&gt; Explain why does last code failed to pass the Test Function , and how to fix it . &lt;/Think&gt; &lt;Code&gt; Your code here . DO make sure the output is a single function that integrates all components. &lt;/Code&gt; &lt;Planning&gt; A detailed step-by-step explanation of the code's workflow. &lt;/Planning&gt; &lt;Main Function Name&gt; The name of the main function that integrates all components. &lt;/Main Function Name&gt; Provide the code with the same indicator and structure as shown in Instructions . DO NOT return any test cases or example usages in your code! Listing 19: LLM-CG: Prompt for code refinement.F SAMPLE TM-GENERATED TEST CASESThis section provides concrete examples of test cases generated by the TM agent (SciCode example; first subproblem of problem 4, using Qwen3-32B), following the rebuttal supplementary material format. validates the correctness of the incomplete Cholesky factorization function using a small symmetric positive definite matrix with known structure and sparsity . The input matrix is : Cholesky factor $K$ should be sparse , preserving the zero pattern from $A$. The exact Cholesky decomposition would give :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Model Performance Comparison on SciCode with various backbone models</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Without Knowledge</cell><cell cols="2">With Knowledge</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Without Knowledge</cell><cell cols="2">With Knowledge</cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>Method</cell><cell>Sub (%)</cell><cell>Main (%)</cell><cell>Sub (%)</cell><cell cols="2">Main (%) Model</cell><cell>Method</cell><cell>Sub (%)</cell><cell>Main (%)</cell><cell>Sub (%)</cell><cell>Main (%)</cell></row><row><cell>Qwen3-8b</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>13.2 24.7(87.1%)</cell><cell>0 4.6</cell><cell>19.8 27.4(38.4%)</cell><cell>1.5 4.6</cell><cell>GPT-4o</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>24.1 37.2(54.3%)</cell><cell>1.5 7.7</cell><cell>33.7 40.6(20.4%)</cell><cell>7.7 10.8</cell></row><row><cell>Qwen3-14b</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>17.7 30.6(72.9%)</cell><cell>1.5 6.2</cell><cell>25.0 32.6(30.4%)</cell><cell>6.2 6.2</cell><cell>Deepseek-v3</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>27.8 40.3(45.0%)</cell><cell>3.1 10.8</cell><cell>38.8 42.4(9.28%)</cell><cell>10.8 12.3</cell></row><row><cell>Qwen3-32b</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>18.4 33.0(79.3%)</cell><cell>0 6.2</cell><cell>27.4 36.1(31.8%)</cell><cell>7.7 7.7</cell><cell>Deepseek-R1</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>29.6 41.0(38.5%)</cell><cell>4.6 10.8</cell><cell>37.8 43.1(14.0%)</cell><cell>10.8 13.8</cell></row><row><cell>Qwen3-next-80b-a3b-instruct</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>21.5 37.5(74.4%)</cell><cell>3.1 9.2</cell><cell>32.6 38.5(18.1%)</cell><cell>12.3 10.8</cell><cell>Claude-sonnet-4</cell><cell>Baseline Ours</cell><cell>31.3 42.7(36.4%)</cell><cell>7.7 13.8</cell><cell>38.8 43.8(12.9%)</cell><cell>10.8 13.8</cell></row><row><cell>Qwen3-235B-A22b-</cell><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>30.6</cell><cell>4.6</cell><cell>37.2</cell><cell>10.8</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Instruct</cell><cell>Ours</cell><cell>38.9(27.1%)</cell><cell>9.2</cell><cell>41.0(10.2%)</cell><cell>10.8</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results on ScienceAgentBench using GPT-4o as base model with/without prior knowledge, compare with two different agent frameworks and baseline.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Direct</cell><cell>11.8</cell><cell>82.6</cell><cell>52.9</cell><cell>10.8</cell><cell>83.8</cell><cell>41.2</cell></row><row><cell>OpenHands CodeAct</cell><cell>19.6</cell><cell>83.1</cell><cell>78.4</cell><cell>27.5</cell><cell>86.3</cell><cell>73.5</cell></row><row><cell>Self-Debug</cell><cell>22.6</cell><cell>84.4</cell><cell>83.3</cell><cell>23.5</cell><cell>85.6</cell><cell>71.6</cell></row><row><cell>LCP(Ours)</cell><cell>26.5</cell><cell>85.1</cell><cell>90.2</cell><cell>27.5</cell><cell>86.4</cell><cell>87.3</cell></row></table><note><p>Method SR(w/o) CBS(w/o) VER(w/o) SR(w/) CBS(w/) VER(w/)</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Pass@1 score comparison of various competing methods</figDesc><table><row><cell>Models</cell><cell>HumanEval</cell><cell>HumanEval-ET</cell><cell>MBPP</cell><cell>MBPP-ET</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Foundation Models (Zero-Shot)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Incoder (6.7B)</cell><cell>15.2</cell><cell>11.6</cell><cell>17.6</cell><cell>14.3</cell></row><row><cell>CodeLlama (34B)</cell><cell>51.8</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>69.3</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>GPT-3.5-turbo</cell><cell>57.3</cell><cell>42.7</cell><cell>52.2</cell><cell>36.8</cell></row><row><cell>Claude-instant-1</cell><cell>31.1</cell><cell>28.1</cell><cell>26.9</cell><cell>19.9</cell></row><row><cell>GPT-4-turbo</cell><cell>57.9</cell><cell>48.8</cell><cell>63.4</cell><cell>47.5</cell></row><row><cell>GPT-4</cell><cell>67.6</cell><cell>50.6</cell><cell>68.3</cell><cell>52.2</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Agentic and Prompting Strategies (GPT-3.5-turbo)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Few-Shot</cell><cell>67.7 (18.2%)</cell><cell>54.9 (28.6%)</cell><cell>65.8 (26.1%)</cell><cell>48.3 (31.2%)</cell></row><row><cell>CoT</cell><cell>44.6 (-22.2%)</cell><cell>37.2 (-12.9%)</cell><cell>46.1 (-11.7%)</cell><cell>34.8 (-5.4%)</cell></row><row><cell>ReAct</cell><cell>56.9 (-0.7%)</cell><cell>49.4 (15.7%)</cell><cell>67.0 (28.4%)</cell><cell>45.9 (24.7%)</cell></row><row><cell>Reflexion</cell><cell>68.1 (18.8%)</cell><cell>50.6 (18.5%)</cell><cell>70.0 (34.1%)</cell><cell>47.5 (29.1%)</cell></row><row><cell>MapCoder</cell><cell>80.5(40.5%)</cell><cell>77.4(81.3%)</cell><cell>78.9(51.1%)</cell><cell>54.4(47.8%)</cell></row><row><cell>AgentCoder</cell><cell>79.9(39.4%)</cell><cell>77.4(81.3%)</cell><cell>89.9(72.2%)</cell><cell>89.1(142.1%)</cell></row><row><cell>CodeCoR</cell><cell>86.6(51.1%)</cell><cell>80.5(88.5%)</cell><cell>79.2(51.7%)</cell><cell>65.2(77.2%)</cell></row><row><cell>LCP (Ours)</cell><cell>88.4(54.3%)</cell><cell>84.1(97.0%)</cell><cell>91.1(74.5%)</cell><cell>86.4(134.8%)</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Agentic and Prompting Strategies (GPT-4)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Reflexion</cell><cell>91.0 (34.6%)</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>77.1 (12.9%)</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>Self-Debugging</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>80.6 (18.0%)</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>Self-Collaboration</cell><cell>90.2 (33.4%)</cell><cell>70.7 (39.7%)</cell><cell>78.9 (15.5%)</cell><cell>62.1 (19.0%)</cell></row><row><cell>MetaGPT</cell><cell>85.9 (27.1%)</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>87.7 (28.4%)</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>AgentCoder</cell><cell>96.3(42.5%)</cell><cell>86.0(70.0%)</cell><cell>91.8(34.4%)</cell><cell>91.8(75.9%)</cell></row><row><cell>CodeCoR</cell><cell>94.5(39.8%)</cell><cell>83.5(65.0%)</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>LCP (Ours)</cell><cell>96.95(43.4%)</cell><cell>88.41(74.7%)</cell><cell>92.51(35.4%)</cell><cell>89.70(71.8%)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Pass@1 accuracy of multi-agent framework (LPW) compared with baseline and LDB on APPS benchmark across different difficulty levels using GPT-4o as the LLM backbone. profile, characterized by several key features: a numerical x coordinate denoting the distance from the profile's origin, serving as a primary input; a numerical y value representing the elevation at that distance, which is the target variable for prediction; and a categorical feature, "Dominant Wave Direction" (e.g., "ENE", "E"), necessitating encoding for model integration. Additional numerical columns are present, representing other relevant physical or environmental parameters that can be incorporated as supplementary features to enhance the predictive model's performance.D.1.2 USER'S PROMPT FOR BEACH PROFILE PREDICTIONPlease refer to the Bruun model and the Dean model to build a mathematical model to discuss the change of sea level height with respect to the distance from the starting point , and build a deep learning model based on our data . The following is our data path and structure :</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Difficulty Level Baseline LDB LPW LCP (Ours)</cell></row><row><cell>Introductory</cell><cell>63.8</cell><cell>78.7</cell><cell>87.2</cell><cell>92.1</cell></row><row><cell>Interview</cell><cell>43.5</cell><cell>52.2</cell><cell>65.2</cell><cell>77.5</cell></row><row><cell>Competition</cell><cell>17.4</cell><cell>28.3</cell><cell>34.8</cell><cell>38.0</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">D ADDITIONAL CASE STUDY DETAILS</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="5">This section provides supplementary information for the case studies presented in the main paper,</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">including detailed experimental setups, prompts, generated code, and further results. To guarantee a</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">fair and interpretable comparison, we use GPT-4o as the unified base model across Cursor, Windsurf,</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">and our framework during the case studies.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note><p><p><p><p><p><p>D.1 CASE STUDY 1: BEACH PROFILE PREDICTION</p>D.1.1 EXPERIMENTAL SETUP</p>The dataset utilized for this beach profile prediction study is organized into distinct training and testing sets, containing 536 and 242 rows respectively. Each data row represents a measurement point along a beach</p>x: A numerical column representing the distance from a profile 's origin ; this is a primary input for predicting y. y: A numerical column representing the elevation ; this is the target variable for prediction . Dominant Wave Direction: This is a categorical ( string ) type column (e . g ., values like "ENE", "E", "NE"). This column will require appropriate encoding. All other relevant columns you might select as features are expected to be in numerical ( integer or float ) format .</p>Create the code directly and The script should not run the main training or evaluation logic directly when the script file is executed . Instead , it should define all necessary functions with a main function main() that can be run WITHOUT ANY input. DO NOT USE tensorflow. Use provided data path in your code.</p>Listing 1: Prompt used for beach profile prediction.</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Windsurf LCP (ours)    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Dice Score</cell><cell>0.6627</cell><cell>0.7232</cell><cell>0.7185</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Training time 127.9s</cell><cell>131.6s</cell><cell>36.2s</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Comparison of Dice scores on test data with code generated by different frameworks.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>You are an expert agent specialized in decomposing code generation tasks into structured , detailed , and clear subtasks and then give a detailed overall plan based on your defined subtasks . Given a simple high-level task description , your job is to break it down into logical subtasks that clearly illustrate the workflow and ensure easy understanding and execution .</figDesc><table><row><cell>Each decomposed subtask should aim to create a function or class as a reusable</cell></row><row><cell>component contributing to the overall task . If the provided task is too simple or</cell></row><row><cell>atomic to require multiple components, your decomposition should only contain a single</cell></row><row><cell>component.</cell></row><row><cell>Your output must strictly follow the format below:</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;components&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>{</cell></row><row><cell>"component_1": {</cell></row><row><cell>" step_task_description ": str ,</cell></row><row><cell>" input_format ": [[ type , shape or null ]],</cell></row><row><cell>"output_format ": [[ type , shape or null ]],</cell></row><row><cell>"work_flow": [ str ],</cell></row><row><cell>" test_case_generation_advise ": [ str ]</cell></row><row><cell>},</cell></row><row><cell>"component_2": {</cell></row><row><cell>" step_task_description ": str ,</cell></row><row><cell>" input_format ": [[" type ", shape or null ]],</cell></row><row><cell>"output_format ": [[" type ", shape or null ]],</cell></row><row><cell>"work_flow": [ str ],</cell></row><row><cell>" test_case_generation_advise ": [ str ]</cell></row><row><cell>},</cell></row><row><cell>...</cell></row><row><cell>}</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;/components&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt; overall_plan &gt;</cell></row><row><cell>{</cell></row><row><cell>" input_format ": [[" type ", shape or null ]],</cell></row><row><cell>"output_format ": [[" type ", shape or null ]],</cell></row><row><cell>"components": [ str ],</cell></row><row><cell>"plan ": [ str ],</cell></row><row><cell>" test_case_generation_advise ": [ str ]</cell></row><row><cell>}</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;/ overall_plan &gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&gt; Here are additional detailed explanations of each field :</cell></row><row><cell>{advice}</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;advice_end&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>Now, please provide the refined task description . Output only the refined task</cell></row><row><cell>description itself , without any extra conversational text or tags .</cell></row><row><cell>Refined Task Description :</cell></row><row><cell>Listing 14: LLM-TM: Prompt for prior knowledge refinement.</cell></row><row><cell>E.1.2 PROMPT FOR TASK DECOMPOSITION</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3. ** Test Case Diversity ** :-Cover all provided advisories .-Include at least one test per advisory and one for each test type where applicable . ### Output Format: For each test case , you need to firstly define the Test Types to indicate what type of test case you are going to create and then give the reasoning and explanation of the test case . After that , generate the test function based on the your reasoning . For each test function , return with following structure : &lt;Type&gt; Pick one of correctness | edge_case| runtime | component_check|error_handling &lt;/Type&gt; &lt;Planning&gt; Introduce how would you design the test function . Specify the purpose of the test function and the reasoning behind it . Explain step by step why your test case is correct and what is the expected output . &lt;/Planning&gt; &lt;Code&gt; def test_case (func) : # Your test function code here return True or False as test result , and a message &lt;/Code&gt; If you are going to create multiple test cases , please separate them with &lt; separator &gt; tag . {example_text} Generate test cases that rigorously validate the function 's behavior , code structure , and performance. You MUST strictly follow the output format and structure . The generated test functions MUST be runnable function that use another python function as its parameter and it should output both the Test result (True or False</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>The computations in this research were performed using the CFFF platform of <rs type="institution">Fudan University</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <ref type="bibr">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr">39]</ref><p>, <ref type="bibr">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr">35,</ref><ref type="bibr">38,</ref><ref type="bibr">39]</ref>] Action: <ref type="bibr">[[38]</ref>, <ref type="bibr">[39]</ref>, <ref type="bibr">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr">35,</ref><ref type="bibr">45,</ref><ref type="bibr">46,</ref><ref type="bibr">50,</ref><ref type="bibr">51]</ref>] Listing 12: Single example about code processing</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E PROMPTS USED FOR LARGE LANGUAGE MODELS (LLMS)</head><p>This section details the specific prompts provided to the Large Language Models (LLMs) for various sub-tasks within our framework. These prompts are displayed to mimic structured textual input. The complete function should take the input arguments as specified in the overall plan and return the output as specified .</p><p>Please add as much comments as possible to your code to explain the logic and any critical steps .</p><p>We compute the first row: </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-4" />
		<title level="m">Anthropic. Claude sonnet 4</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Program synthesis with large language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Austin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Augustus</forename><surname>Odena</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maxwell</forename><surname>Nye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>Bosma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Henryk</forename><surname>Michalewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Dohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carrie</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Terry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Quoc</forename><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2108.07732</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Llms4synthesis: Leveraging large language models for scientific synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hamed</forename><surname>Babaei Giglou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D'</forename><surname>Jennifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sören</forename><surname>Souza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Auer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th ACM/IEEE Joint Conference on Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>the 24th ACM/IEEE Joint Conference on Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language models are few-shot learners</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Ryder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melanie</forename><surname>Subbiah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jared</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Prafulla</forename><surname>Dhariwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arvind</forename><surname>Neelakantan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Shyam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Girish</forename><surname>Sastry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Askell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems(NeurIPS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1877" to="1901" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evaluating large language models trained on code</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Tworek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heewoo</forename><surname>Jun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qiming</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Henrique</forename><surname>Ponde De Oliveira Pinto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jared</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harri</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuri</forename><surname>Burda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Brockman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2107.03374</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teaching large language models to self-debug</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xinyun</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maxwell</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Schärli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Denny</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2304.05128</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Scienceagentbench: Toward rigorous assessment of language agents for data-driven scientific discovery</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ziru</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shijie</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuting</forename><surname>Ning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qianheng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Boshi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Botao</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yifei</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zeyi</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zitong</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2410.05080</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Palm: Scaling language modeling with pathways</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aakanksha</forename><surname>Chowdhery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sharan</forename><surname>Narang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>Bosma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gaurav</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Barham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hyung</forename><forename type="middle">Won</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Gehrmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">240</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-collaboration code generation via chatgpt</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yihong</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xue</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhi</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ge</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Codescore: Evaluating code generation by learning code execution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yihong</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jiazheng</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xue</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ge</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhuo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhi</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deepseek-r1: Incentivizing reasoning capability in llms via reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dejian</forename><surname>Daya Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haowei</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Junxiao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruoyu</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Runxin</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qihao</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shirong</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peiyi</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2501.12948</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reasoning with language model is planning with world model</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shibo</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haodi</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><forename type="middle">Jiahua</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daisy</forename><forename type="middle">Zhe</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhiting</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2305.14992</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Measuring coding challenge competence with apps</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Hendrycks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Basart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Saurav</forename><surname>Kadavath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mantas</forename><surname>Mazeika</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Akul</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ethan</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Collin</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samir</forename><surname>Puranik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Horace</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dawn</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2105.09938</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Metagpt: Meta programming for multi-agent collaborative framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sirui</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xiawu</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuheng</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinlin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ceyao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zili</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Ka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shing</forename><surname>Yau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zijuan</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liyang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2308.00352</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Codecot and beyond: Learning to program and test like a developer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dong</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qingwen</forename><surname>Bu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heming</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2308.08784,23</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Agentcoder: Multi-agent-based code generation with iterative testing and optimisation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dong</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jie</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Luck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qingwen</forename><surname>Bu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuhao</forename><surname>Qing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heming</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2312.13010</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jen-Tse</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jiaxu</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tailin</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xuhui</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zixi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wenxuan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Youliang</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>Michael R Lyu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2408.00989</idno>
		<title level="m">On the resilience of llm-based multi-agent collaboration with faulty agents</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Hurst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Lerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Goucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Perelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Ramesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aidan</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Akila</forename><surname>Ostrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Welihinda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alec</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Radford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2410.21276</idno>
		<title level="m">Gpt-4o system card</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mapcoder: Multi-agent code generation for competitive problem solving</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ashraful</forename><surname>Md</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohammed</forename><forename type="middle">Eunus</forename><surname>Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Md</forename><surname>Ali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Parvez</forename><surname>Rizwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2405.11403</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-planning code generation with large language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xue</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yihong</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lecheng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qiwei</forename><surname>Shang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ge</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhi</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wenpin</forename><surname>Jiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structured chain-of-thought prompting for code generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jia</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ge</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yongmin</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhi</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competition-level code generation with alphacode</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yujia</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Junyoung</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nate</forename><surname>Kushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Schrittwieser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rémi</forename><surname>Leblond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Eccles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Keeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Felix</forename><surname>Gimeno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Agustin</forename><surname>Dal Lago</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">378</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6624</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1092" to="1097" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aixin</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bei</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bingxuan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bochao</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chengda</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chenggang</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chengqi</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chenyu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chong</forename><surname>Ruan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2412.19437</idno>
		<title level="m">Deepseek-v3 technical report</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Codegen: An open large language model for code with multi-turn program synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Nijkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hiroaki</forename><surname>Hayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lifu</forename><surname>Tu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yingbo</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Silvio</forename><surname>Savarese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Caiming</forename><surname>Xiong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2203.13474</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeevana</forename><surname>Theo X Olausson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chenglong</forename><surname>Priya Inala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Armando</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Solar-Lezama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2306.09896</idno>
		<title level="m">Is self-repair a silver bullet for code generation?</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Codecor: An llm-based self-reflective multi-agent framework for code generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruwei</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hongyu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2501.07811</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Communicative agents for software development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xin</forename><surname>Cong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cheng</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Weize</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yusheng</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Juyuan</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhiyuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maosong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2307.07924</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Code generation with alphacodium: From prompt engineering to flow engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tal</forename><surname>Ridnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dedy</forename><surname>Kredo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Itamar</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2401.08500</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Code llama: Open foundation models for code</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Baptiste Roziere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fabian</forename><surname>Gehring</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sten</forename><surname>Gloeckle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Itai</forename><surname>Sootla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Xiaoqing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yossi</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jingyu</forename><surname>Adi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Romain</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tal</forename><surname>Sauvestre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Remez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2308.12950</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reflexion: Language agents with verbal reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Noah</forename><surname>Shinn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Federico</forename><surname>Cassano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ashwin</forename><surname>Gopinath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karthik</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shunyu</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems(NeurIPS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8634" to="8652" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scicode: A research coding benchmark curated by scientists</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Minyang</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luyu</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shizhuo</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xinan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cunwei</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xuefei</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roland</forename><surname>Haas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pan</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kittithat</forename><surname>Krongchon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30624" to="30650" />
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intervenor: Prompt the coding ability of large language models with the interactive chain of repairing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hanbin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhenghao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shuo</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ganqu</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ning</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhiyuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ge</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Consortium for Reliability and Reproducibility</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CoRR)</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chain-of-thought prompting elicits reasoning in large language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xuezhi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dale</forename><surname>Schuurmans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>Bosma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ed</forename><surname>Chi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Quoc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Denny</forename><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24824" to="24837" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qingyun</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gagan</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jieyu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yiran</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Beibin</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erkang</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xiaoyun</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shaokun</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jiale</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2308.08155</idno>
		<title level="m">Autogen: Enabling next-gen llm applications via multi-agent conversation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The ai scientist-v2: Workshop-level automated scientific discovery via agentic tree search</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yutaro</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Tjarko Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cong</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shengran</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jakob</forename><surname>Foerster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Clune</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Ha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2504.08066</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">An</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anfeng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Baosong</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Beichen</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Binyuan</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chang</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chengen</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chenxu</forename><surname>Lv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2505.09388</idno>
		<title level="m">Qwen3 technical report</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tree of thoughts: Deliberate problem solving with large language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shunyu</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dian</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Izhak</forename><surname>Shafran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karthik</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11809" to="11822" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">React: Synergizing reasoning and acting in language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shunyu</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dian</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nan</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Izhak</forename><surname>Shafran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karthik</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-Edit: Fault-Aware Code Editor for Code Generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kechi</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhuo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jia</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ge</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhi</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/2023.acl-long.45</idno>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2305.04087</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 61st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)</title>
		<meeting>the 61st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="769" to="787" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Agent4s: The transformation of research paradigms from the perspective of large language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Boyuan</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zerui</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhe</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yiwen</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cunshi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mengwei</forename><surname>Qu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Lei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhen</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2506.23692</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Language agent tree search unifies reasoning acting and planning in language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andy</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Shlapentokh-Rothman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haohan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yu-Xiong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2310.04406</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
