<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Channel-Adaptive Edge AI: Maximizing Inference Throughput by Adapting Computational Complexity to Channel States</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Graduate Student Member, IEEE</roleName><forename type="first">Jierui</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Member, IEEE</roleName><forename type="first">Jianhao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Fellow, IEEE</roleName><forename type="first">Kaibin</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Channel-Adaptive Edge AI: Maximizing Inference Throughput by Adapting Computational Complexity to Channel States</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">EC542923D8F80D1B6235CA0C772E05A0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2026-03-07T16:46+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Edge inference</term>
					<term>channel-adaptive AI</term>
					<term>adaptive transmission</term>
					<term>mixture model</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Integrated communication and computation (IC 2 ) has emerged as a new paradigm for enabling efficient edge inference in sixth-generation (6G) networks. However, the design of IC 2 technologies is hindered by the lack of a tractable theoretical framework for characterizing end-to-end (E2E) inference performance. The metric is highly complicated as it needs to account for both channel distortion and artificial intelligence (AI) model architecture and computational complexity. In this work, we address this challenge by developing a tractable analytical model for E2E inference accuracy and leveraging it to design a channeladaptive AI algorithm that maximizes inference throughput, referred to as the edge processing rate (EPR), under latency and accuracy constraints. Specifically, we consider an edge inference system in which a server deploys a backbone model with early exit, which enables flexible computational complexity, to perform inference on data features transmitted by a mobile device. The proposed accuracy model characterizes high-dimensional feature distributions in the angular domain using a Mixture of von Mises (MvM) distribution. This leads to a desired closed-form expression for inference accuracy as a function of quantization bit-width and model traversal depth, which represents channel distortion and computational complexity, respectively. Building upon this accuracy model, we formulate and solve the EPR maximization problem under joint latency and accuracy constraints, leading to a channel-adaptive AI algorithm that achieves full IC 2 integration. The proposed algorithm jointly adapts transmit-side feature compression and receive-side model complexity according to channel conditions to maximize overall efficiency and inference throughput. Experimental results demonstrate its superior performance as compared with fixed-complexity counterparts.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>The sixth-generation (6G) mobile networks are expected to enable ubiquitous edge artificial intelligence (AI) services (also known as edge inference), supporting applications such as autonomous driving, smart cities, robotics, and healthcare <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>- <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. A typical edge inference system comprises a device that extracts features from sensed data and transmits them to an edge server; the server then performs inference using a pre-trained AI model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. To meet the stringent performance demands of 6G, researchers have adopted an integrated communication-and-computation (IC 2 ) design approach aimed at optimizing end-to-end (E2E) metrics such as latency, accuracy, and throughput <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Since both communication and computation operations significantly influence E2E performance, they are inherently coupled and require joint control. The joint control is especially critical in high-mobility scenarios, where both C 2 operations must be dynamically adapted to rapidly changing channel conditions to support high-throughput, low-latency edge AI services. However, due to the lack of tractable design methods, existing techniques predominantly enable only partial C 2 adaptation, namely either adaptive communication or adaptive computation but not both. To bridge this gap, this paper proposes a tractable IC 2 framework, termed channel-adaptive AI, which jointly adjusts computational complexity and transmission compression based on channel state information (CSI), with the goal of maximizing E2E inference throughput while satisfying constraints on latency and inference accuracy.</p><p>In classical communication theory, channel adaptation, namely adjusting the modulation and coding scheme based on the channel state, is a key mechanism for realizing the optimal rate-reliability tradeoff in the presence of fading <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. While traditional techniques are application agnostic, recent 6G research has introduced channel-adaptive transmission schemes tailored specifically to edge inference systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Such schemes aim to ensure reliable and efficient delivery of data features through mechanisms such as scheduling, bandwidth allocation, and power control <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>- <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. To further reduce communication overhead, a device can partition a feature vector into multiple segments and transmit them progressively in order of decreasing importance until a target inference confidence is achieved <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. In distributed sensing-and-inference systems, the scalability of multi-access is addressed by over-the-air computation (AirComp), which exploits waveform superposition to perform in-air feature aggregation and thereby enables simultaneous access <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. Realizing AirComp typically relies on distributed transmitpower adaptation to mitigate computation errors caused by channel distortion <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. Overall, these prior approaches primarily focus on communication adaptation and do not provide the full C 2 adaptation required to optimize E2E performance.</p><p>Recent research has begun to explore fully adaptive IC 2 designs. A representative class of techniques is split inference, where a global AI model is partitioned into two parts deployed at the device and the server for cooperative inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>. The traversal depth of the model on the device side affects the number of features to be transmitted and thus arXiv:2603.03146v1 [cs.IT] 3 Mar 2026 the communication overhead. It also determines the device's computation energy consumption, while the communication energy counterpart depends on the channel condition <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>.</p><p>Combining these facts motivates the development of methods to adapt the model-splitting point to the channel state, jointly with bandwidth allocation or device selection <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>- <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>.</p><p>Another main line of work focuses on deploying so-called early-exiting models in edge inference systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>- <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref>. Such a model is a neural network architecture that provides intermediate outputs ("early exits") at multiple depths. By enabling multi-stage predictions, the model offers a finegrained mechanism for controlling accuracy, latency, and computation load, which is particularly useful for resourceconstrained or real-time applications <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. The inherent tradeoff of an early-exiting model is that intermediate features become increasingly discriminative as the traversal depth increases, leading to higher inference accuracy but also greater computational cost. Deploying a large-scale backbone model at the server facilitates meeting heterogeneous quality-ofservice and E2E latency requirements across users <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>. For example, in a multiuser system with heterogeneous requirements, the C 2 latency of different users can be jointly controlled via bandwidth allocation and exit-point selection to maximize inference throughput <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>. Owing to this flexibility, an early-exiting model is adopted in this work to realize the proposed adaptive AI framework.</p><p>The main challenge of designing the proposed adaptive AI techniques lies in the lack of a theoretical framework that quantifies the C 2 relationships among inference accuracy, computational complexity, and channel distortion. Such a framework would enable the derivation of a simple, closedform control scheme to facilitate rapid channel adaptation, supporting the stringent requirements of low-latency applications. However, this critical framework is currently absent from the literature, as explained below. Prior work on edge inference typically assumes reliable communication without explicit latency guarantees (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>). In contrast, lowlatency applications must satisfy strict latency constraints. On one hand, under unfavorable channel conditions, transmitted data must either be compressed more aggressively (incurring larger quantization errors), or suffer increased transmission errors. On the other hand, increasing the traversal depth of on-device models can improve inference robustness to such data distortions (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref>), but at the cost of higher computational complexity/latency <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>. Therefore, developing efficient channel-adaptive AI techniques requires the aforementioned theoretical framework to properly account for these trade-offs. To address this issue, existing research on earlyexiting models characterizes the impact of traversal depth on accuracy through empirically measured accuracy-latency pairs <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>. This enables the joint control of bandwidth allocation and exit-point selection to be formulated as a combinatorial optimization problem, which is then solved via efficient tree search algorithms. However, this method is inefficient in highly dynamic environments, as every change in channel state or user set triggers the execution of a computationally intensive tree search. Moreover, such empirical approaches are limited in more complex scenarios, such as the one considered here where multiple interdependent factors, including accuracy, complexity, and channel distortion, must be simultaneously addressed.</p><p>To address the preceding challenge, the main contribution of this work lies in developing a novel, tractable model of inference accuracy for early-exiting models and applying it to derive closed-form schemes for jointly adapting the traversal depth and quantization bit-width to the channel state. Thereby, the resulting adaptive-AI framework achieves maximum E2E throughput under constraints on air latency and inference accuracy. Focusing on a popular classification task, we consider a single-user edge inference system described shortly. In this system, a shallow model running on the edge device performs feature extraction, while a large-scale early-exiting model is deployed at the server to provide a flexible trade-off between discernibility and computational complexity/latency. Prior to transmission, the extracted features are quantized at the device with an adjustable bit-width to control communication overhead. To evaluate the E2E throughput of the system, we define the edge processing rate (EPR) as the ratio of the number of transmitted and processed bits to the E2E inference latency, subject to a target inference accuracy and air latency. The key contributions and findings of this paper are summarized as follows.</p><p>• Tractable Modeling of Inference Accuracy: The proposed statistical model establishes a closed-form relationship between E2E inference accuracy and the distribution of the projection of high-dimensional features onto a single-dimensional angular domain. Motivated by experimental observations, a key feature of the model is representing the feature distribution in the angular domain as a Mixture of von Mises (MvM) distribution, with an adjustable linear-rate parameter fitted using real data. The model's tractability is reflected in enabling the use of the maximum a posteriori (MAP) decision rule to derive closed-form expressions for inference accuracy at different traversal depths and under various levels of channel distortion. Validation against experimental results shows that the theoretical predictions closely match observed outcomes. Both theoretical and empirical results confirm the trend that inference accuracy improves with increased traversal depth at the server but degrades as quantization errors grow due to deteriorating channel conditions. This accuracy model provides the essential analytical foundation for the adaptive AI strategies developed in the subsequent work. • Channel-adaptive AI Schemes: Building on the preceding accuracy model, we formulate an optimization problem aimed at maximizing the EPR under constraints on air latency and E2E inference accuracy. By solving this problem, a closed-form adaptive AI scheme is derived that jointly selects the quantization bit-width on the device and the traversal depth at the server based on the instantaneous channel signal-to-noise ratio (SNR).</p><p>The solution approach involves a continuous relaxation (CR) of the discrete variables, namely, traverse depth and quantization bit-width, and subsequent rounding to obtain a practical implementation. As shown by the derived scheme, it is optimal to control the bit-width linearly proportionally to the channel capacity, and select the minimal traversal depth that satisfies the accuracy constraint given the corresponding quantization distortion. • Experiments: Using the CIFAR-10 dataset, we compare the proposed adaptive AI scheme with a non-adaptive baseline that employs fixed quantization bit-widths and traversal depths. The results demonstrate consistent performance improvements of the adaptive scheme across all SNR levels. Notably, at a transmit SNR of 25 dB, our scheme achieves twice the EPR of the non-adaptive approach at a target accuracy of 95%. Additionally, by relaxing the target accuracy from 95% to 85%, the EPR of the proposed scheme can be further increased by 14.2%. This highlights its flexibility in effectively balancing inference accuracy and communication efficiency. The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. Section II introduces the models and metrics. The tractable model for inference and the channel-adaptive AI are presented in Section III and Section IV, respectively. Experimental results are provided in Section V, followed by concluding remarks in Section VI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. MODELS AND METRICS</head><p>Consider an edge inference system as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">2</ref>, in which the edge device extracts the features of source data and transmits them to the edge server for inference. The inference result will subsequently be sent back to the edge device. The inference model, communication model, and performance metrics are introduced in the following subsections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Inference Model</head><p>We consider a classification problem that aims to predict the label ŷ ∈ J = {1, 2, ..., J} (J ⩾ 2) of an image sample x ∈ R D . A pretrained backbone model Φ = {G, F } is split into two parts: a shallow model G is on the edge device, and a deep model F with L layers is on the edge server, with the ℓ-the layer in F denoted by F ℓ . Modern backbone models typically contain a sequence of blocks with identical architecture (e.g., a set of residual blocks within the same stage of the ResNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31]</ref>). G serves as a feature extractor to transform the sample x to latent features of z = G(x) ∈ R d . The features are then transmitted over a channel and received at the edge server, as z. At the edge server, traversing the model F , the received features z are gradually transformed to become more discriminative (see e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>), thereby resulting in increasingly higher inference accuracy.</p><p>1) Adaptive Exit: Controllable inference latency can be realized by early exiting from the server model F <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>. The specific ℓ for an inference task is determined by the channel state and target accuracy to realize the concept of adaptive exit. After traversing the first ℓ layers,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">z become zℓ = (F ℓ • • • • • F 1 )(z).</formula><p>2) Intermediate Classifiers: Early exit point of the backbone model is attached to an intermediate classifier, which is a shallow CNN model denoted as F cnn,ℓ for exiting at F ℓ . Note that the conventional design outputs the predicted label via a Softmax classifier. In contrast, for the proposed design, F cnn,ℓ (•) = (atan2 • ϕ ℓ )(•) first transforms zℓ into a 2D feature vector via the nonlinear projection ϕ ℓ , and then outputs the associated angular feature via the atan2 function 1 : θℓ = F cnn,ℓ (z ℓ ) ∈ (-π, π]. The angular features from different classes exhibit distinct distributions in the angular space. Denote the conditional probability density function (PDF) of θℓ given class j ∈ J as p ℓ ( θℓ |j), which is modeled in the next section. The maximum a posteriori (MAP) criterion is employed to estimate the class (i.e., label) of θℓ as ŷℓ = arg max j∈J Pr(j| θℓ ), which, under the assumption of uniform priors, simplifies to ŷℓ = arg max j∈J p ℓ ( θℓ |j).</p><p>(1)</p><p>3) Backbone and Classifier Training: First, the backbone model F is trained using the training set {(x i , y i )} N i=1 with x i being the i-th sample, y i ∈ J being its ground truth label, and N being the sample number, and the cross entropy as the loss function <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref>. As for the proposed intermediate classifier F cnn,ℓ , the training procedure is as follows. The training samples {x i } N i=1 are transformed into high-dimensional intermediate features {z ℓ,i } N i=1 using G, followed by</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">F ℓ • • • • • F 1 .</formula><p>To facilitate classification and for ease of modeling, we resort to representation learning to train F cnn,ℓ for mapping {z ℓ,i } i=N i=1 to angles { θℓ,i } i=N i=1 . Specifically, for each class j ∈ J , we assign a predefined class centroid µ j ∈ (-π, π]. In the angular space, the angular distance is measured as</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">d(β 1 , β 2 ) = min |β 1 -β 2 |, 2π -|β 1 -β 2 | .<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Then, we define the loss function over the training set {(z ℓ,i , µ yi )} N i=1 as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">L △ = 1 - 1 N N i=1 cos d( θℓ,i , µ yi ) .<label>(3)</label></formula><p>1 atan2(y, x) ≜ arg(x+iy) is the argument of the complex number x+iy <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref>.</p><p>&lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " r 9 W f P B s D g 4 M 6 h 5 Y m S m V x p l M S p b M = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V D L S g M x F L 1 T X 7 W + q i 7 d B I v g q s y I r 2 X B j c s K 9 o F t K Z n 0 T h u a y Q x J R q h D / 8 K N C 0 X c + j f u / B s z 7 S y 0 9 U D g c M 6 9 5 N z j x 4 J r 4 7 r f T m F l d W 1 9 o 7 h Z 2 t r e 2 d 0 r 7 x 8 0 d Z Q o h g 0 W i U i 1 f a p R c I k N w 4 3 A d q y Q h r 7 A l j + + y f z W I y r N I 3 l v J j H 2 Q j q U P O C M G i s 9 d E N q R n 6 Q P k 3    Feature extractor &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " V X U J w B 0       Then, minimizing this loss function by training encourages angular samples to cluster around their centroids corresponding to their ground-truth labels. We demonstrate that employing this loss does not degrade learning performance compared to standard cross entropy; rather, it enhances training robustness, thereby leading to improved overall results, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">3</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">V i 8 U 9 Z A n 1 I j w W L G Q E g 5 Z G Z s M F x g O a u x G G i R / m j 0 V R H 5 l N u 2 X P Y C 0 T p y J N V K E z M r / c I C Z p R A U Q j p U a O n Y C X o 4 l M M J p U X d T R R N M p n h M h 5 o K H F H l 5 b P w h X W i l c A K Y 6 m f A G u m / t 7 I c a R U F v l 6 s s y o F r 1 S / M 8 b p h B e e z k T S Q p U k P m h M O U W x F b Z h B U w S Q n w T B N M J N N Z L T L B E h P Q f Z U l O I t f X i a 9 s 5 Z z 2 b q 4 O 2 + 2 7 a q O G j p C x + g U O e g K t d E t 6 q A u I i h D z + g V v R l P x o v x b n z M R</formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">L J W 1 + K K u a H q 8 v P F U d f B 7 Z E g = " &gt; A A A B 6 H i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h V 3 x d Q x 4 8 Z i A e U C y h N l J b z J m d n a d m R X C k i / w 4 k E R r 3 6 S N / / G S b I H T S x o K K q 6 6 e 4 K E s G 1 c d 1 v Z 2 V 1 b X 1 j s 7 B V 3 N 7 Z 3 d s v H R w 2 d Z w q h g 0 W i 1 i 1 A 6 p R c I k N w 4 3 A d q K Q R o H A V j C 6 n f q t J 1 S a x / L e j B P 0 I z q Q P O S M G i v V H 3 u l s l t x Z y D L x M t J G X L U e q W v b j 9 m a Y T S M E G 1 7 n h u Y v y M K s O Z w E m x m 2 p M K B v R A X Y s l T R C 7 W e z Q y f k 1 C p 9 E s b K l j R k p v 6 e y G i k 9 T g K b G d E z V A v e l P x P 6 + T m v D G z 7 h M U o O S z R e F q S A m J t O v S Z 8 r Z E a M L a F M c X s r Y U O q K D M 2 m 6 I N w V t 8 e Z k 0 z y v e V e W y f l G u u n k c B T i G E z g D D 6 6 h C n d Q g w Y w Q H i G V 3 h z H p w X 5 9 3 5 m L e u O P n M E f y B 8 / k D 2 X O M 7 Q = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; q &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " t s Z u L J W 1 + K K u a H q 8 v P F U d f B 7 Z E g = " &gt; A A A B 6 H i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h V 3 x d Q x 4 8 Z i A e U C y h N l J b z J m d n a d m R X C k i / w 4 k E R r 3 6 S N / / G S b I H T S x o K K q 6 6 e 4 K E s G 1 c d 1 v Z 2 V 1 b X 1 j s 7 B V 3 N 7 Z 3 d s v H R w 2 d Z w q h g 0 W i 1 i 1 A 6 p R c I k N w 4 3 A d q K Q R o H A V j C 6 n f q t J 1 S a x / L e j B P 0 I z q Q P O S M G i v V H 3 u l s l t x Z y D L x M t J G X L U e q W v b j 9 m a Y T S M E G 1 7 n h u Y v y M K s O Z w E m x m 2 p M K B v R A X Y s l T R C 7 W e z Q y f k 1 C p 9 E s b K l j R k p v 6 e y G i k 9 T g K b G d E z V A v e l P x P 6 + T m v D G z 7 h M U o O S z R e F q S A m J t O v S Z 8 r Z E a M L a F M c X s r Y U O q K D M 2 m 6 I N w V t 8 e Z k 0 z y v e V e W y f l G u u n k c B T i G E z g D D 6 6 h C n d Q g w Y w Q H i G V 3 h z</formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">d Z Q o h g 0 W i U i 1 f a p R c I k N w 4 3 A d q y Q h r 7 A l j + + y f z W I y r N I 3 l v J j H 2 Q j q U P O C M G i s 9 d E N q R n 6 Q P k 3 7 5 Y p b d W c g y 8 T L S Q V y 1 P v l r + 4 g Y k m I 0 j B B t e 5 4 b m x 6 K V W G M 4 H T U j f R G F M 2 p k P s W C p p i L q X z h J P y Y l V B i S I l H 3 S k J n 6 e y O l o d a T 0 L e T W U K 9 6 G X i f 1 4 n M c F 1 L + U y T g x K N v 8 o S A Q x E c n O J w O u k B k x s Y Q y x W 1 W w k Z U U W Z s S S V b g r d 4 8 j J p n l W 9 y + r F 3 X m l 5 u Z 1 F O E I j u E U P L i C G t x C H R r A Q M I z v M K b o 5 0 X 5 9 3 5 m I 8 W n H z n E P 7 A + f w B + w + R F A = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; x &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " n 3 E R 7 C H Y x m 1 3 5 d O G v k p / E s o t H 0 M = " &gt; A A A B 8 3 i c b V B N S 8 N A E N 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 n E r 2 P B i 8 c K 9 g O a U D b b a b t 0 s w m 7 E y G E / g 0 v H h T x 6 p / x 5 r 9 x 2 + a g r Q 8 G H u / N M D M v T K Q w 6 L r f T m l t f W N z q 7 x d 2 d n d 2 z + o H h 6 1 T Z x q D i 0 e y 1 h 3 Q 2 Z A C g U t F C i h m 2 h g U S i h E 0 7 u Z n 7 n C b Q R s X r E L I E g Y i M l h o I z t J L v j x n m 2 b T v g 5 T 9 a s 2 t u 3 P Q V e I V p E Y K N P v V L 3 8 Q 8 z Q C h V w y Y 3 q e m 2 C Q M 4 2 C S 5 h W / N R A w v i E j a B n q W I R m C C f 3 z y l Z 1 Y Z 0 G G s b S m k c / X 3 R M 4 i Y 7 I o t J 0 R w 7 F Z 9 m b i f 1 4 v x e F t k A u V p A i K L x Y N U 0 k x p r M A 6 E B o 4 C g z S x j X w t 5 K + Z h p x t H G V L E h e M s v r 5 L 2 R d 2 7 r l 8 9 X N Y a b h F H m Z y Q U 3 J O P H J D G u S e N E m L c J K Q Z / J K 3 p z U e</formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">X 6 2 R v Q 0 R D 2 u z t F j B 4 M s E = " &gt; A A A B 6 H i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h V 3 x d Q x 4 0 G M C 5 g H J E m Y n v c m Y 2 d l l Z l Y I S 7 7 A i w d F v P p J 3 v w b J 8 k e N L G g o a j q p r s r S A T X x n W / n Z X V t f W N z c J W c X t n d 2 + / d H D Y 1 H G q G D Z Y L G L V D q h G w S U 2 D D c C 2 4 l C G g U C W 8 H o d u q 3 n l B p H s s H M 0 7 Q j + h A 8 p A z a q x U v + u V y m 7 F n Y E s E y 8 n Z c h R 6 5 W + u v 2 Y p R F K w w T V u u O 5 i f E z q g x n A i f F b q o x o W x E B 9 i x V N I I t Z / N D p 2 Q U 6 v 0 S R g r W 9 K Q m f p 7 I q O R 1 u M o s J 0 R N U O 9 6 E 3 F / 7 x O a s I b P + M y S Q 1 K N l 8 U p o K Y m E y / J n 2 u k B k x t o Q y x e 2 t h A 2 p o s z Y b I o 2 B G / x 5 W X S P K 9 4 V 5 X L + k W 5 6 u Z x F O A Y T u A M P L i G K t x D D R r A A O E Z X u H N e X R e n H f n Y 9 6 6 4 u Q z R / A H z u c P m c u M w w = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; G &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " o P l J 0 z N M 7 i + 7 O s A B F z A 2 v P 4 e o G M = " &gt; A A A B + 3 i c b V D L S s N A F L 2 p r 1 p f t S 7 d D B b B h Z R E f C 0 L g r i s Y B / Q h j C Z T t q h k 0 m Y m Y g l 5 F f c u F D E r T / i z r 9 x 0 m a h r Q c G D u f c y z 1 z / J g z p W 3 7 2 y q t r K 6 t b 5 Q 3 K 1 v b O 7 t 7 1 f 1 a R 0 W J J L R N I h 7 J n o 8 V 5 U z Q t m a a 0 1 4 s K Q 5 9 T r v + 5 C b 3 u 4 9 U K h a J B z 2 N q R v i k W A B I 1 g b y a v W b r 1 0 E G I 9 l m F K h M h O n c y r 1 u 2 G P Q N a J k 5 B 6 l C g 5 V W / B s O I J C E V m n C s V N + x Y + 2 m W G p G O M 0 q g 0 T R G J M J H t G + o Q K H V L n p L H u G j o 0 y R E E k z R M a z d T f G y k O l Z q G v p n M Y 6 p F L x f / 8 / q J D q 7 d l I k 4 0 V S Q + a E g 4 U h H K C 8 C D Z m k R P O p I Z h I Z r I i M s Y S E 2 3 q q p g S n M U v L 5 P O W c O 5 b F z c n 9 e b d l F H G Q 7 h C E 7 A g S t o w h 2 0 o A 0 E n u A Z X u H N y q w X 6 9 3 6 m I + W r G L n A P 7 A + v w B F Y q U b Q = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; F cnn,1 Exit 1 Intermediate linear classifier Exit 2 … Exit L &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " h K 4 n N Y 5 j 6 o E l E 5 H 3 0 o n S b t z 0 x v U = " &gt; A A A B + 3 i c b V D L S s N A F L 3 x W e u r 1 q W b Y B F c S E m K r 2 V B E J c V 7 A P a E C b T S T t 0 Z h J m J m I J + R U 3 L h R x 6 4 + 4 8 2 + c t F l o 6 4 G B w z n 3 c s + c I G Z U a c f 5 t l Z W 1 9 Y 3 N k t b 5 e 2 d 3 b 3 9 y k G 1 o 6 J E Y t L G E Y t k L 0 C K M C p I W 1 P N S C + W B P G A k W 4 w u c n 9 7 i O R i k b i Q U 9 j 4 n E 0 E j S k G G k j + Z X q r Z 8 O O N J j y V M s R H b W y P x K z a k 7 M 9 j L x C 1 I D Q q 0 / M r X Y B j h h B O h M U N K 9 V 0 n 1 l 6 K p K a Y k a w 8 S B S J E Z 6 g E e k b K h A n y k t n 2 T P 7 x C h D O 4 y k e U L b M / X 3 R o q 4 U l M e m M k 8 p l r 0 c v E / r 5 / o 8 N p L q Y g T T Q S e H w o T Z u v I z o u w h 1 Q S r N n U E I Q l N V l t P E Y S Y W 3 q K p s S 3 M U v L 5 N O o + 5 e 1 i / u z 2 t N p 6 i j B E d w D K f g w h U 0 4 Q 5 a 0 A Y M T / A M r / B m Z d a L 9 W 5 9 z E d X r G L n E P 7 A + v w B F w + U b g = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; F cnn,2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " t V 9 C a 0 A 1 f 9 Z 8 U k J J 9 t X r R V 8 V G n Y = " &gt; A A A B / X i c b V D L S s N A F L 2 p r 1 p f 8 b F z M 1 g E V y U R X 8 u C G 5 c V 7 A O a E C a T S T t 0 8 m B m I r Q h + C t u X C j i 1 v 9 w 5 9 8 4 b b P Q 1 g M D h 3 P u 5 Z 4 5 f s q Z V J b 1 b V R W V t f W N 6 q b t a 3 t n d 0 9 c / + g I 5 N M E N o m C U 9 E z 8 e S c h b T t m K K 0 1 4 q K I 5 8 T r v + 6 H b q d x + p k C y J H 9 Q 4 p W 6 E B z E L G c F K S 5 5 5 5 C j G A 5 o 7 E V Z D P 8 w n R e H Z n l m 3 G t Y M a J n Y J a l D i Z Z n f j l B Q r K I x o p w L G X f t l L l 5 l g o R j g t a k 4 m a Y r J C A 9 o X 9 M Y R 1 S 6 + S x 9 g U 6 1 E q A w E f r F C s 3 U 3 x s 5 j q Q c R 7 6 e n I a U i 9 5 U / M / r Z y q 8 c X M W p 5 m i M Z k f C j O O V I K m V a C A C U o U H 2 u C i W A 6 K y J D L D B R u r C a L s F e / P I y 6 Z w 3 7 K v G 5 f 1 F v W m V d V T h G E 7 g D G y 4 h i b c Q Q v a Q G A C z / A K b 8 a T 8 W K 8 G x / z 0 Y p R 7 h z C H x i f P y Y t l a E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; z1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " E k G O T I e / O 1 t S V p E I o V D R 9 W q 6 u 8 o = " &gt; A A A B / X i c b V D L S s N A F J 3 4 r P U V H z s 3 w S K 4 K k n x t S y 4 c V n B P q A J Y T K 5 a Y d O J m F m I r S h + C t u X C j i 1 v 9 w 5 9 8 4 a b P Q 1 g M D h 3 P u 5 Z 4 5 Q c q o V L b 9 b a y s r q 1 v b F a 2 q t s 7 u 3 v 7 5 s F h R y a Z I N A m C U t E L 8 A S G O X Q V l Q x 6 K U C c B w w 6 A a j 2 8 L v P o K Q N O E P a p y C F + M B p x E l W G n J N 4 9 d R V k I u R t j N Q y i f D K d + g 3 f r N l 1 e w Z r m T g l q a E S L d / 8 c s O E Z D F w R R i W s u / Y q f J y L B Q l D K Z V N 5 O Q Y j L C A + h r y n E M 0 s t n 6 a f W m V Z C K 0 q E f l x Z M / X 3 R o 5 j K c d x o C e L k H L R K 8 T / v H 6 m o h s v p z z N F H A y P x R l z F K J V V R h h V Q A U W y s C S a C 6 q w W G W K B i d K F V X U J z u K X l 0 m n U X e u 6 p f 3 F 7 W m X d Z R Q S f o F J 0 j B 1 2 j J r p D L d R G B E 3 Q M 3 p F b 8 a T 8 W K 8 G x / z 0 R W j 3 D l C f 2 B 8 / g A n s Z W i &lt; / l</formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">V O 8 1 S T k h n A = " &gt; A A A B / X i c b V D L S s N A F J 3 4 r P U V H z s 3 w S K 4 K o n 4 W h b c u H B R w T 6 g C W E y u W m H T i Z h Z i K 0 o f g r b l w o 4 t b / c O f f O G m z 0 N Y D A 4 d z 7 u W e O U H K q F S 2 / W 0 s L a + s r q 1 X N q q b W 9 s 7 u + b e f l s m m S D Q I g l L R D f A E h j l 0 F J U M e i m A n A c M O g E w 5 v C 7 z y C k D T h D 2 q U g h f j P q c R J V h p y T c P X U V Z C L k b Y z U I o n w 8 m f h 3 v l m z 6 / Y U 1 i J x S l J D J Z q + + e W G C c l i 4 I o w L G X P s V P l 5 V g o S h h M q m 4 m I c V k i P v Q 0 5 T j G K S X T 9 N P r B O t h F a U C P 2 4 s q b q 7 4 0 c x 1 K O 4 k B P F i H l v F e I / 3 m 9 T E X X X k 5 5 m i n g Z H Y o y p i l E q u o w g q p A K L Y S B N M B N V Z L T L A A h O l C 6 v q E p z 5 L y + S 9 l n d u a x f 3 J / X G n Z Z R w U d o W N 0 i h x 0 h R r o F j V R C x E 0 R s / o F b 0 Z T 8 a L 8 W 5 8 z E a X j H L n A P 2 B 8 f k D T x m V v A = =</formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">i m k q m k A p i T N f 3 E g x y o p F T w S a V X m p Y Q u i Y D F n X U k U k M 0 E + O 3 j i n l h l 4 E a x t q X Q n a m / J 3 I i j c l k a D s l w Z F Z 9 K b i f 1 4 3 x e g 6 y L l K U m S K z h d F q X A x d q f f u w O u G U W R W U K o 5 v Z W l 4 6 I J h R t R h U b g r / 4 8 j J p n 9 X 9 y / r F 3 X m t 4 R V x l O E I j u E U f L i C B t x C E 1 p A Q c I z v M</formula><formula xml:id="formula_10">J B Q 1 H V T X d X E E t h 0 H W / n c L a + s b m V n G 7 t L O 7 t 3 9 Q P j x q m S j R j D d Z J C P d C a j h U o S 8 i Q I l 7 8 S a U x V I 3 g 4 m t z O / / c S 1 E V H 4 g G n M f U V H o R g K R t F K j 7 0 x x S y d 9 m v 9 c s W t u n O Q V e L l p A I 5 G v 3 y V 2 8 Q s U T x E J m k x n Q 9 N 0 Y / o x o F k 3 x a 6 i W G x 5 R N 6 I h 3 L Q 2 p</formula><formula xml:id="formula_11">L q J Y T G h Y z J k H U s V k c w E 2 e z g i X t i l b 4 7 i L Q t h e 5 M / T 2 R E W l M K k P b K Q m O z K I 3 F f / z O g k O r o O M q z h B p u h 8 0 S A R L k b u 9 H u 3 z z W j K F J L C N X c</formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">u E J Z / g x Y M i X v 0 i b / 6 N k 2 Q P m l j Q U F R 1 0 9 0 V J I J r 4 7 r f z s r q 2 v r G Z m G r u L 2 z u 7 d f O j h s 6 j h V D B s s F r F q B 1 S j 4 B I b h h u B 7 U Q h j Q K B r W B 0 M / V b T 6 g 0 j + W j G S f o R 3 Q g e c g Z N V Z 6 u O 1 V e 6 W y W 3 F n I M v E y 0 k Z c t R</formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">9 R x q h g 2 W C x i 1 Q 6 o R s E l N g w 3 A t u J Q h o F A l v B 6 G r q t x 5 R a R 7 L B z N O 0 I / o Q P K Q M 2 q s d H / d u + 2 V K 2 7 V n Y H 8 J V 5 O K p C j 3 i t / d v s x S y O U h g m q d c d z E + N n V B n O B E 5 K 3 V R j Q t m I D r B j q a Q R a j + b n T o h R 1 b p k z B W t q Q h M / X n R E Y j</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Communication Model</head><p>Consider the transmission of the feature vector, z, by the device. Each element of z, say z, is quantized into q bits by uniform quantization <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>. Specifically, let [c min , c max ] be the quantization range. Let the quantization step be ∆ = cmax-cmin 2 q</p><p>. Then the quantized z is given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">z = c min + ∆ • ⌊ z-cmin ∆ ⌋ + 1 2</formula><p>, where ⌊•⌋ is the floor function. The quantization level ⌊ z-cmin ∆ ⌋ is mapped to a binary code of q bits. The binary codes of all features are concatenated to form a bit stream, which is then modulated and transmitted. The i-th symbol received at the server is given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">y i = h √ px i + n i ,<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where x i is the i-th transmitted symbol, p is the transmit power, h is the channel coefficient, and n i ∼ CN (0, ν 2 n ) is the independent and identically distributed (IID) additive white Gaussian noise (AWGN). It is assumed that h remains constant over the duration of transmitting a single feature vector. The communication rate is calculated using the Shannon equation as r = B log 2 (1+γ), where B is the bandwidth and γ = p|h| 2 ν 2 n is the receive SNR <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref>. Then, the communication latency for transmitting z, denoted as T comm , is</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">T comm = dq B log 2 (1 + γ) . (<label>5</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_17">)</formula><p>To support a low-latency application, a latency constraint is enforced: T comm ≤ T max , where T max is the maximal air latency. The edge server demodulates the received symbols to recover the bit stream and reconstruct the feature vector as z.</p><p>The overhead of downloading the inference result (i.e., scalar label) back to the device is negligible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Performance Metrics</head><p>The system performance can be evaluated using two metrics: inference accuracy and throughput (i.e., EPR). The inference accuracy to be modeled in the next section is denoted as P (q, ℓ), which is affected by the bit-width q and traversal depth ℓ at the edge server. Next, the EPR is defined as follows. The E2E inference latency is the summation of communication latency and computation latency: T total = T comm + T comp , where T comp combines inference time at both the device and server. Mathematically,</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">T comp = Λ ν d + ℓ k=1 λ(k) ν s ,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where λ(k) is the number of floating point operations (FLOPs) in layer k on the server while Λ is the FLOPs of the device model, and ν d and ν s are the computation speed of the device and server, respectively. Since the layers in the backbone model have the same structure, we can write T comp in (6) as an affine function w.r.t. ℓ, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> T</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">comp = b 1 ℓ + b 2 ,<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where b 1 and b 2 are constants.</p><p>Definition 1 (Edge Processing Rate (EPR)). Given the bitwidth q, the traversal depth ℓ, and the inference accuracy P (q, ℓ), the EPR is defined as the number of bits that the edge inference system can process per unit time:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">EPR △ = dq T comm + T comp .<label>(8)</label></formula><p>By substituting ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_16">5</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_19">7</ref>) into (8),</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">EPR(q, ℓ) = dq dq B log 2 (1+γ) + b 1 ℓ + b 2 . (<label>9</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_22">)</formula><p>Remark 1 (Comparison with traditional metrics).</p><p>• EPR versus communication rate: Compared with the classic communication rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, EPR is constrained   by both the computation and communication latency. EPR is upper bounded by the communication rate, i.e., B log 2 (1 + γ). When the computation speed approaches infinity, the EPR approaches the communication rate. • EPR versus inference accuracy: According to Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref> and<ref type="figure"></ref> (9), it can be observed that an increased traversal depth, ℓ, enhances the inference accuracy but lowers the EPR. When ℓ = 1, the accuracy is at its minimum while EPR is at its maximum. The reverse is true when ℓ is large.</p><p>To balance the preceding tradeoff, it is necessary to determine the optimal traversal depth, which is the topic of Section IV.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. TRACTABLE MODELING OF INFERENCE ACCURACY</head><p>In this section, we establish a tractable model of inference accuracy to facilitate the design of channel-adaptive AI. First, the mixture of von Mises model is proposed to represent the distribution of angular features. Then, we use the model to characterize inference accuracy in relation to traversal depth and the bit-width.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Modeling the Distribution of Angular Features</head><p>Consider the AI model described in Section II-A and the angular features output at an arbitrary exit point. In this subsection, we describe a statistical model for their distribution, which is useful for subsequent classification accuracy analysis. First, we adopt a representation learning method from the existing literature to train the model such that the angular features form clusters in the angular domain, as illustrated in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">4</ref> 2 and <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref>. One modification we make on the method is to introduce a set of given centroids into the learning process to improve classification accuracy. For simplicity, we assume uniform class priors and choose the centroids to be equally spaced in angle; for other class-prior distributions, the centroid locations can be adjusted accordingly. Based on the above learning method, it has been shown in the literature that the angular features of a single class j are approximately distributed in the angular domain (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">4(b)</ref>), according to 2 The trained backbone model with the proposed intermediate classifiers is utilized to transform the samples in the validation set. The effects of quantization are omitted. The traversal depth is set to ℓ = 37, but the distribution pattern is also valid for other values. The CIFAR-10 dataset and ResNet-152 are utilized in the demonstrations in this section, with the details described in the experimental settings in Sec. V-A. a von Mises (vM) distribution defined by the following PDF <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref> </p><formula xml:id="formula_23">p ℓ ( θℓ |j) = exp κ (j) ∆,ℓ cos ( θℓ -µ j ) 2πI 0 (κ (j) ∆,ℓ ) , θℓ ∈ (-π, π],<label>(10)</label></formula><p>where I 0 (s) = 1 π π 0 exp (s cos (x)) dx is the modified Bessel function of the first kind and order 0, µ j is the centroid of the j-th class, and κ (j) ∆,ℓ is a concentration parameter related to quantization noise and traversal depth. Note that κ (j) ∆,ℓ is inversely related to dispersion, so 1/κ (j) ∆,ℓ plays a role analogous to variance. We denote the distribution as θℓ |j ∼ vM(µ j , κ (j) ∆,ℓ ). Accordingly, the multi-class angular features follow a mixture of von Mises (MvM) distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">p ℓ ( θℓ ) = 1 J J j=1 p ℓ ( θℓ |j).<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Most classes in practical datasets typically exhibit a similar level of concentration, as demonstrated in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">4</ref>(b). Consequently, a common simplifying assumption of uniform κ ∆,ℓ , i.e., κ</p><p>∆,ℓ = κ ∆,ℓ , ∀j, is adopted in the literature and also made in the model in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[44]</ref>. The parameter κ ∆,ℓ in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref> is the most important parameter of the MvM model. It can be estimated from a dataset using the procedure described in Appendix A.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Model Parameter w.r.t. Traversal Depth and Channel Distortion</head><p>Consider the key parameter, κ ∆,ℓ , of the MvM model in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref>. As demonstrated in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">5</ref>, it is related to traversal depth and quantization bit-width, which determine the levels of computational complexity and channel distortion, respectively. In this subsection, we investigate these relationships. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Estimated Value of κ</head><p>Error free q = 8 q = 9 q = 10 q = 11 (a) κ ∆,ℓ w.r.t. traversal depth.  1) Modeling Distortion w.r.t. Bit-width: In the considered edge inference system, the distortion on the feature vector mainly comes from quantization errors, which is significant under the latency constraint. We model this distortion elementwise using a uniform distribution: ϵ ∼ U (-∆/2, ∆/2) <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45]</ref>. The variance is thus given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">σ 2 ∆ (q) = (c max -c min ) 2 12 • 2 2q . (<label>12</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_27">)</formula><p>How the distortion propagates through the neural network is quantified in the sequel.</p><p>2) κ ∆,ℓ w.r.t. Traversal Depth: First, assume quantization errors are negligible, i.e., σ 2 ∆ = 0. Let κℓ denote the concentration parameter in this scenario. Based on the empirical results shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">5</ref>(a), the relationship between κℓ and the traversal depth, ℓ, can be modeled as the following linear function</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">κℓ = c 1 ℓ + c 2 ,<label>(13)</label></formula><p>where the coefficients c 1 and c 2 can be estimated by the least square method <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[46]</ref>.</p><p>3) κ ∆,ℓ w.r.t. Traversal Depth and Channel Distortion: Next, based on the preceding models, the desired relations are quantified in the following proposition.</p><p>Proposition 1. Assume a data sample to transmit belongs to j, given the transversal depth, ℓ, at the server, and quantization distortion with variance σ 2 ∆ , the channel-distorted angular feature, θℓ |j, follows a vM distribution with centroid µ j and concentration parameter κ ∆,ℓ , i.e., vM(µ j , κ ∆,ℓ ). µ j is fixed from the training process and remains unchanged, and κ ∆,ℓ is given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">κ ∆,ℓ = A -1 A(κ ℓ )A(ρ ∆,ℓ ) ,<label>(14)</label></formula><p>where A(•)</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">△ = I1(•) I0(•) , A -1 (•) is its inversion, I 1 (s) =</formula><p>1 π π 0 cos x exp (s cos x) dx is the modified Bessel function of the first kind and order 1, and ρ ∆,ℓ = A -1 exp -σ 2 ∆ a ℓ /2 . Moreover, a ℓ ≜ E z a ℓ (z) ⊤ a ℓ (z) represents the expected squared norm of the gradient a ℓ ≜ ∇f ℓ (z), where the model propagation function is</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">f ℓ (•) ≜ (F cnn,ℓ • F ℓ • • • • • F 1 )(•).</formula><p>According to experimental results (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_30">14</ref>), a ℓ decreases exponentially w.r.t. ℓ, therefore we approximate a ℓ by</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">a ℓ = c 3 exp(-c 4 ℓ), (<label>15</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_33">)</formula><p>where c 3 and c 4 are estimated positive constants.</p><p>Proof. See Appendix B.</p><p>Remark 2 (Effects of channel distortion). The result in <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14)</ref> indicates that the presence of noise always makes the κ ∆,ℓ smaller and correspondingly reduces the discernibility of data features. The reason is as follows. First of all, the function A(•) is monotonically increasing, so is its reverse, A -1 (•). As a result, ρ ∆,ℓ defined in the proposition statement is a monotone decreasing function of the error variance σ 2 ∆ . It follows that κ ∆,ℓ decreases as σ 2 ∆ grows, as claimed earlier, resulting in lower classification accuracy. For a sanity check, as σ 2 ∆ → 0, we have ρ ∆,ℓ → ∞ and hence A -1 A(κ ℓ )A(ρ ∆,ℓ ) → A -1 A(κ ℓ ) • 1 → κℓ , yielding κ ∆,ℓ → κℓ as in the ideal case of no quantization error.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Inference Accuracy Analysis</head><p>Building on the preceding model of angular feature distribution, the performance of the inference system is analyzed with the result stated in the following theorem. Theorem 1. Consider the MvM model of angular feature distribution in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref> with the parameter κ ∆,ℓ given in Proposition ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_29">14</ref>) and the MAP detection method in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref>. The inference accuracy for channel distortion σ 2 ∆ and traversal depth ℓ is given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) = π J 0 exp κ ∆,ℓ cos (x) πI 0 (κ ∆,ℓ ) dx,<label>(16)</label></formula><p>where the model parameter κ ∆,ℓ is simplified as</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">κ ∆,ℓ = A -1 A(c 1 ℓ + c 2 ) exp(-σ 2 ∆ c 3 exp(-c 4 ℓ)/2) .</formula><p>Proof. Since all clusters are equidistant and possess identical shapes, the decision boundaries are located at the midpoints between neighboring cluster centers. The classification accuracy for a specific class is obtained by integrating its PDF over its corresponding decision region; by symmetry, this accuracy is identical across all classes. Taking class j as an example, the classification accuracy is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">Pr d(µ j , θℓ ) &lt; π J = π J -π J exp (κ ∆,ℓ cos x) 2πI 0 (κ ∆,ℓ ) dx, which equals π J 0 exp (κ ∆,ℓ cos x) πI0(κ ∆,ℓ )</formula><p>dx, due to the symmetry of the integrand. Assume equal class priors, then this expression represents the overall system accuracy, yielding <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(16)</ref>. Finally, substituting ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_28">13</ref>), <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14)</ref>, and ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_32">15</ref>) into ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>) yields the desired result.</p><p>The behavior of ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>) is depicted in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_17">6</ref>, while its properties are characterized as follows.</p><p>1) Monotonicity: The monotonicity of the accuracy function in <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(16)</ref>, which is useful for the subsequent design, is stated as follows.</p><p>Corollary 1 (Monotonicity of Accuracy Function). The function P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>) is monotonically decreasing w.r.t. J and σ 2 ∆ , and monotonically increasing w.r.t. κ ∆,ℓ and ℓ. Proof. See Appendix C.</p><p>The above properties are aligned with intuition. First, as the number of object classes, J, increases, their discernibility drops and thus the accuracy decreases. Second, increasing the distribution parameter, κ ∆,ℓ , causes the features belonging to the same class to be more concentrated, which enhances the classification accuracy. These results suggest that one viable approach to improve the classification performance is to either increase κ ∆,ℓ or decrease J. Third, Corollary 1 states that traversing more model layers at the receiver yields higher inference accuracy, while increased channel distortion (i.e., larger σ 2 ∆ ) entails the opposite. This suggests higher computational complexity can help to mitigate the adverse effect of channel distortion, which is the fundamental principle underpinning the design in the next section.</p><p>2) Asymptotics: To understand the limits of the inference accuracy, we derive the following results.</p><p>Corollary 2. The range of the inference accuracy is P ∈ ( 1 J , 1). When κ ∆,ℓ → 0, P → 1 J , and when κ ∆,ℓ → ∞, P → 1.</p><p>Proof. See Appendix. D. Similar as Corollary 1, the results in Corollary 2 agree with intuition. Note that the accuracy of 1  J corresponds to that of random guessing, indicating zero discernibility of data feature.</p><p>To better understand the asymptotic properties of inference accuracy, its scaling law is derived as shown below.</p><p>Proposition 2. In the case free of distortion (σ 2 ∆ = 0), as the traversal depth ℓ → ∞, the accuracy follows the scaling law:</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">P (0, ℓ) ∼ 1- √ 2 J π 3/2 √ c 1 ℓ + c 2 exp - π 2 2J 2 (c 1 ℓ + c 2 ) . (<label>17</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_38">)</formula><p>Proof. See Appendix E.</p><p>This result indicates that the classification error probability decays exponentially as ℓ grows. Therefore, increasing computational complexity is a highly effective way of enhancing inference performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. CHANNEL-ADAPTIVE AI ALGORITHM</head><p>In the preceding section, we develop a theoretical model of inference accuracy. In this section, the model is leveraged to design the adaptive AI algorithm that maximized throughput in terms of EPR under constraints on accuracy and latency. Finally, the algorithm performance is discussed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Problem Formulation</head><p>The design of adaptive AI algorithm can be formulated as an optimization problem to maximize the EPR under constraints in inference accuracy and air latency. Mathematically, (P1) max q∈Q, ℓ∈Li EPR(q, ℓ) (18a)</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">s. t. P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) ≥ P 0 , (18b) T comm ≤ T max ,<label>(18c)</label></formula><p>where EPR(q, ℓ), P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ), and T comm are given by ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_21">9</ref>), ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>), and (5), respectively. Moreover, P 0 and T max denote the target inference accuracy and maximal air latency, respectively. Let Q △ = {0, 1, 2, . . . , Q} be an available set of bit-widths, and L △ = {ℓ 1 , ℓ 2 , . . . , ℓ i } ⊆ {1, 2, . . . , L} be the set of exit layers that supports adaptive exit with ℓ 1 &lt; ℓ 2 &lt; • • • &lt; ℓ i . L is analogous a modulation constellation. The solution of (P1) is the channel-adaptive AI algorithm in the sequel, which determines the EPR-maximizing bit-width and traversal depth.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Channel-Adaptive AI Algorithm</head><p>To solve (P1), we first relax the variables to be continuous and provide the corresponding solution in IV-B1. Subsequently, its relaxation is removed in IV-B2 to yield the desired algorithm.</p><p>1) Continuous Relaxation: For tractability, we first assume q and ℓ to be continuous, and refer to the resultant algorithm as channel-adaptive AI with continuous relaxation (CR). The associated EPR upper bounds its counterpart from solving (P1). With CR, the continuous quantization can be realized as follows. Suppose there are d features to be quantized: if αd features are quantized into q 0 bits and (1α)d features are quantized into (q 0 + 1) bits with q 0 being and integer, then the average bits is q △ = αq 0 + (1α)(q 0 + 1) = q 0 + 1α. In this setting <ref type="foot" target="#foot_1">3</ref> , the expected variance of quantization distortion in (12) becomes</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">σ 2 ∆ (q) =α (c max -c min ) 2 12 • 2 2q0 + (1 -α) (c max -c min ) 2 12 • 2 2(q0+1) , = 1 + 3α 4 (c max -c min ) 2 12 • 2 2q0 ,<label>(19)</label></formula><p>where q 0 = ⌊q⌋ and α = 1 -(qq 0 ). Note that when α = 1, (19) reduces to <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(12)</ref>. Under the CR, we solve (P1) as follows.</p><p>We first analyze the objective function of (P1):</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">EPR = dq T comm + T comp = B log 2 (1 + γ) 1 + Tcomp Tcomm .<label>(20)</label></formula><p>This suggests that maximizing T comm and minimizing T comp can maximize EPR. To achieve these two goals, we first formulate two intermediate optimization problems (P2) and (P3) as follows.</p><p>Maximizing T comm fundamentally requires maximizing q. Therefore, (P2) is formulated as</p><formula xml:id="formula_42">(P2) max q q (21a) s.t. dq B log 2 (1 + γ) ≤ T max .<label>(21b)</label></formula><p>Next, we consider minimizing T comp , which fundamentally requires minimizing ℓ as T comp increases monotonically w.r.t. ℓ. Hence, (P3) is formulated as</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">(P3) min ℓ ℓ (22a) s. t. P (σ 2 ∆ (q * ), ℓ) ≥ P 0 ,<label>(22b)</label></formula><p>where q * is the solution to (P2).</p><p>Proposition 3 (Solution to (P1)). Solving (P2) first and then solving (P3) yields the solution to (P1).</p><p>Proof. We prove this by contradiction. Suppose we've obtained the aforementioned solution q * and ℓ * . If there exist some q 0 and ℓ 0 such that the resulting EPR is higher, then we must either have (i) q 0 = q * , or (ii) q 0 &lt; q * , as a result of the constraint (18c). In situation (i), to make EPR higher, we must have ℓ 0 &lt; ℓ * . But this would ruin the constraint (22b) based on the monotonicity. Hence, we omit this situation.</p><p>In situation (ii), the resulting σ 2 ∆ gets higher, which makes ℓ 0 &gt; ℓ * according to the monotonicity of P (σ 2 ∆ (q * ), ℓ). Now that q 0 ≤ q * and ℓ 0 &gt; ℓ * , they contribute to smaller communication latency and higher computation latency, and thus degrade the EPR according to <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(20)</ref>. A contradiction appears here. This completes the proof.</p><p>The solution for (P2) can be straightforwardly obtained as</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">q * = T max B log 2 (1 + γ) d .<label>(23)</label></formula><p>According to Corollary 1, P (σ 2 ∆ (q * ), ℓ) increases monotonically w.r.t. ℓ. Based on this monotonicity, the solution to (P3), ℓ * , can be obtained by solving equation P (σ 2 ∆ (q * ), ℓ) = P 0 w.r.t. ℓ. This can be solved numerically via efficient binary search, and we denote the solution as ℓ * = P -1 (σ 2 ∆ (q * ), P 0 ), where we use P -1 (•, •) to denote the inverse of function P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) w.r.t. ℓ. According to Proposition 3, the solution to (P1) is given by {q * , ℓ * }.</p><p>2) Practical Solution: We remove the CR of q and ℓ to yield the practical channel-adaptive AI algorithm. Proposition 3 poses no requirement on the variable property, and hence, it is applicable in this discrete context as well. Therefore, based on previous results, we can derive the solution to (P2) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_45">q * = ⌊ L max B log 2 (1 + γ) d ⌋ Q ,<label>(24)</label></formula><p>where ⌊x⌋ Q is the floor function that selects the largest number in the set Q less than or equal to x. And subsequently, the solution to (P3) is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_46">ℓ * = P -1 (σ 2 ∆ (q * ), P 0 ) L<label>(25)</label></formula><p>as the solution to (P3), where q * is determined by <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(24)</ref> and ⌈x⌉ L is the ceiling function that selects the smallest number in set L greater than or equal to x. Note that when P -1 (σ 2 ∆ (q * ), P 0 ) &gt; ℓ i , ℓ * does not exist. In this case, we set ℓ * = ℓ i and allow for a zero EPR. Now that we have solved (P1) under practical settings, we summarize the channeladaptive AI algorithm in Algorithm 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Channel-adaptive AI</head><formula xml:id="formula_47">Input: Partitioned backbone model Φ = {G, F }, intermediate CNNs {F cnn,ℓ } ℓ∈L , inference tasks with {x i } N i=1 . 1: for i = 1 to N do 2:</formula><p>Use G to transform x i to z i .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3:</head><p>Calculate the q and ℓ according to <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(24)</ref> and (25).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4:</head><p>Transmit z i based on (4), and the received one is zi . </p><formula xml:id="formula_48">: Use F cnn,ℓ • F ℓ • • • • • F 1 to transform zi to θℓ,i . 6:</formula><p>Obtain the inferred label ŷi based on (1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>7:</head><p>Transmit back the ŷi to edge device. 8: end for Output: Inferred labels {ŷ i } N i=1 for all samples.   C. Discussion on Performance 1) Throughput versus EPR: The performance of channeladaptive AI with CR is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_20">7(a)</ref>. With a fixed accuracy threshold, EPR increases monotonically as SNR increases. Furthermore, when the accuracy threshold is lowered, EPR also increases for a given SNR. The EPR curves in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_20">7</ref>(a) are analogous to those of communication rate relative to SNR at different bit error rates (BERs), where EPR corresponds to the communication rate, and P 0 to BER.</p><p>2) Computational Complexity versus SNR and Accuracy: Since the traversal depth, which determines the receiver complexity, can be calculated when the target accuracy and SNR are set, a visualization of channel-adaptive AI with CR is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_20">7(b</ref>). It can be shown that when the SNR decreases or the target accuracy increases, the required traversal depth increases, because only by trading more computation can the algorithm mitigate the distortion and achieve a satisfactory inference accuracy.</p><p>3) Effect of the Set of Exit Layers: As for the practical channel adaptive AI without CR, we set the target accuracy as P 0 = 0.9 and the considered sets of exit layers are shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">I</ref>. As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_22">8(a)</ref>, as the number of exit layers increases, the EPR also increases. Channel-adaptive AI with CR represents the theoretical limit for the practical one. This is due to the fact that a greater number of exit layers provides more candidates for exit, thereby increasing the potential to reduce computation latency while satisfying the accuracy requirement. Consequently, as the number of exit layers increases, the EPR of the practical channel-adaptive AI without CR can approach that with CR. Additionally, we introduce a non-adaptive algorithm as a benchmark, where the bit-width is fixed, and only one exit layer (i.e., 49) is utilized. Since both parameters remain constant regardless of channel states, this approach is classified as non-adaptive. This is analogous to non-adaptive transmission, where the transmission rate and power are fixed <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. The curves presented in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_22">8</ref>  AI over its non-adaptive counterpart. A visualization of the practical channel-adaptive algorithm is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_22">8(b)</ref>.</p><p>Due to the discrete bit-width and layers, the resulting surface appears stepped, which distinguishes it from channel-adaptive AI with CR. Furthermore, the application of the floor function for q and the ceiling function for ℓ generally results in a greater required traversal depth in practical channel-adaptive AI compared with channel-adaptive AI with CR.  to the channel-adaptive AI algorithm. Offline experiments with the validation dataset are carried out to obtain the mappings between accuracy and traversal depth in different bit-width. Therefore, the bit-width can be calculated based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(24)</ref> and the minimal possible exit layer can be obtained based on the mappings by using the binary search. The candidate layers in different regions are shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">II</ref>. • Benchmarking scheme: We consider a non-adaptive AI algorithm as a benchmarking scheme. For this scheme, the bit-width and traversal depth are fixed regardless of the channel states. For example, we can set q = 12 and ℓ = 37, respectively. Additional combinations of q and ℓ are specified later.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Experimental Settings</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Validation of Inference Accuracy</head><p>As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_23">9</ref>, both the theoretical inference accuracy in ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>) and the experimental accuracy across two sub-datasets show a similar increasing tendency as traversal depth increases; they closely match each other. The theoretical accuracy is slightly more aligned with the experimental accuracy of the validation set, because the hyperparameters are estimated based on it. Nevertheless, since the data distributions of the validation set and the test set are nearly identical, the performance is also similar. This suggests that, considering the channel-adaptive algorithm, the actual inference performance with the test set would not decrease compared to that of the validation set. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_25">10</ref> shows how the inference accuracy is influenced by the number of bit-width and traversal depth. As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_25">10</ref>(a), the inference accuracy increases monotonically w.r.t. the bit-width when the layer is fixed, because a higher bit-width means less distortion on features, which leads to better inference performance. On the other hand, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_25">10(b</ref>), when the bit-width is fixed, more layers mean higher inference accuracy, which aligns with the error-free  Error free q = 8 q = 9 q = 10 q = 11 (b) Inference accuracy w.r.t. ℓ. scenarios. This phenomenon is more obvious when the bitwidth is higher, because the distortion caused by extremely low bit-width yields high randomness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Inference Performance of Channel-adaptive AI</head><p>We compare the performance of channel-adaptive AI with its counterpart, the non-adaptive AI algorithm, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">11</ref>. In Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">11</ref>(a), it can be seen that the EPR of channeladaptive AI increases monotonically w.r.t. both the SNR and the number of exit layers. And the reasons are trivial: higher SNRs allow for higher bit-width and smaller traversal depth, which collaboratively increase the EPR. And when the number of exit layers increases, there is potential that fewer layers could be used while satisfying the accuracy threshold, which increases the EPR. As for the non-adaptive AI algorithm, there is a possibility that the fixed bit-width cannot guarantee the communication constraint, which leads to the zero EPR when the SNR is low. Omitting the fixed bit-width, the nonadaptive AI algorithm can be considered as a special case of channel-adaptive AI, i.e., the number of exit layers is 1. Therefore, its performance is not as good as the channeladaptive AI with more exit layers. Specifically, when the SNR is 15 dB, channel-adaptive AI with 5 exit layers demonstrates a 34.3% higher EPR compared with the non-adaptive algorithm. Furthermore, at an SNR of 25 dB, the performance gain is over 100%. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">11(b)</ref> shows the actual inference accuracy of the schemes in different SNRs. In low-SNR scenarios, the inference accuracy has not reached the target accuracy, as the distortion caused by the channel cannot be mitigated even when all the layers are utilized. Another observation is that in high-SNR scenarios, increasing the number of exit layers decreases the inference accuracy, while still satisfying the accuracy requirement. This illustrates the adaptability of channel-adaptive AI, which sacrifices some accuracy when necessary to achieve a higher EPR. As for the non-adaptive AI algorithm, since the features cannot be transmitted successfully within the transmission period, random guessing is used, which yields an inference accuracy of 1/J = 0.1.</p><p>Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_32">12</ref> illustrates the performance of channel-adaptive AI across different target accuracy levels. The curves align with the expectation that a lower target accuracy permits a higher EPR. Specifically, when the SNR is 25 dB, reducing the target accuracy from 0.95 to 0.9 and 0.85 results in associated EPR increases of 9.04% and 14.2%, respectively. Non-adaptive (q =8, =37)</p><p>Non-adaptive (q =10, =37)</p><p>Non-adaptive (q =12, =37)</p><p>(a) The EPR. Non-adaptive (q =8, =37)</p><p>Non-adaptive (q =10, =37)</p><p>Non-adaptive (q =12, =37) (b) The inference accuracy. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VI. CONCLUDING REMARKS</head><p>In this paper, we present a novel channel-adaptive AI framework that adaptively controls the quantization and computational complexity according to the channel state. Such a computation-communication integrated design maximizes the inference throughput while providing a guarantee on air latency and inference accuracy, thereby supporting latencysensitive edge AI applications. To develop the framework, we propose a tractable model for inference accuracy, wherein the intermediate angular features are modeled as a mixture of von Mises distributions. Experiments demonstrate the superiority of the channel-adaptive AI algorithm compared with its conventional non-adaptive counterpart.</p><p>Several directions for further research merit exploration. First, the effects of fast fading can be incorporated into the communication model. In this context, metrics such as EPR and theoretical accuracy can be replaced with expected values relative to channel realization; the optimization problem can be reformulated accordingly. Additionally, techniques to mitigate unsuccessful inference due to channel outage need to be designed. Furthermore, the joint design of adaptive transmission (i.e., modulation, power control, and beamforming) and adaptive computational complexity is also a promising direction for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>APPENDIX</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Parameter Estimation of MvM</head><p>Getting the exact distribution of the angular features necessitates the estimation of κ ∆,ℓ , with finite samples. We start by investigating the N j samples for class j: θ(j) ℓ,1 , θ(j) ℓ,2 , . . . , θ(j) ℓ,Nj .</p><p>Referring to <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[47]</ref>, a biased estimation of the κ</p><p>∆,ℓ is given by κ</p><formula xml:id="formula_50">(j) ∆,ℓ = A -1 Nj n=1 cos( θ(j) ℓ,n ) 2 + Nj n=1 sin( θ(j) ℓ,n ) 2 .</formula><p>(26) To align with the identical κ assumption, we further estimate the κ ∆,ℓ in the MvM model as</p><formula xml:id="formula_51">κ∆,ℓ = 1 J J j=1 κ(j) ∆,ℓ .<label>(27)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Proof of Proposition 1</head><p>In this subsection, we prove that the channel distorted angular feature θℓ |j follows the vM distribution for arbitrary quantization level and transversal depth. Denote</p><formula xml:id="formula_52">f ℓ (•) = (F cnn,ℓ • F ℓ • • • • • F 1 )(•)</formula><p>be the composite mapping from feature z to angular feature θℓ . The details of the proof are narrated as follows.</p><p>1) Differentiability Assumption: We assume the composite function f ℓ (•) is differentiable w.r.t. the input z. Given that f ℓ (•) comprises the backbone network F ℓ • • • • • F 1 and the intermediate CNN F cnn,ℓ , we examine the differentiability of each component as follows.</p><p>• Backbone: The ResNet-152 backbone employed in this work comprises standard convolutional and pooling layers. Although ReLU activations and max-pooling operations are non-differentiable at specific singularities, these occur on sets of measure zero and are resolved via subgradients. Consequently, we treat the backbone as differentiable.</p><p>• Intermediate CNN: For F cnn,ℓ (•) = (atan2 • ϕ ℓ )(•), the projection ϕ ℓ inherits the differentiability of the backbone network as it shares the same operations. However, the atan2 function operator introduces singularities: it is undefined at the origin and exhibits a discontinuity along the negative real axis (the branch cut), where the output jumps between π and -π. The singularity at the origin is negligible as it constitutes a set of measure zero. The discontinuity can be solved by introducing an auxiliary function f † ℓ (•) that serves as a locally continuous surrogate for f ℓ (•). Specifically, to compensate for the jump at the branch cut, we define f † ℓ (•) ≜ f ℓ (•) -2π for transitions from -π to π, and f † ℓ (•) ≜ f ℓ (•) + 2π for the reverse transition. Accordingly, we define the gradient at the branch cut as ∇f ℓ (z) ≜ ∇f † ℓ (z). Overall, the gradient is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_53">a ℓ = ∇f ℓ (z) = ℓ k=1 ∂F k ∂z k-1 ⊤ ∂ϕ ℓ ∂z ℓ ⊤ 1 ∥v ℓ ∥ 2 -v y v x ,<label>(28)</label></formula><p>where z 0 ≜ z, z k = F k (z k-1 ) for k = 2, • • • , ℓ, and v ℓ = ϕ ℓ (z ℓ ) = [v x , v y ] ⊤ denotes the 2D projected feature. The last term in <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(28)</ref> comes from the standard derivative of atan2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref>. Based on the preceding analysis, we proceed under the assumption that f ℓ (•) is differentiable almost everywhere.</p><p>2) Proof of the Distorted Angular Feature Distribution: Let ϵ = zz denote the quantization distortion vector, modeled as IID uniform random variables with zero mean and variance σ 2 ∆ . Let θℓ ≜ f ℓ (z) represent the undistorted angular feature (when σ 2 ∆ = 0), while θℓ = f ℓ (z) is the distorted one. We analyze the distribution of θℓ using a first-order Taylor expansion in the neighborhood of z:</p><formula xml:id="formula_54">θℓ = f ℓ (z) = f ℓ (z + ϵ)<label>(a)</label></formula><p>≈ θℓ + a T ℓ ϵ mod 2π</p><formula xml:id="formula_55">(b)</formula><p>= θℓ + a T ℓ ϵ mod 2π</p><formula xml:id="formula_56">≜ϵ ℓ mod 2π,<label>(29)</label></formula><p>where (a) comes from the first-order Taylor approximation in the angular domain. Note that when f ℓ (z) approaches ±π, the term θℓ + a T ℓ ϵ may fall outside the range (-π, π]. The modulo operation mod corrects this by wrapping the value back into the valid domain, ensuring angular periodicity. For values already within bounds, the operation leaves them unchanged. (b) comes from the modular arithmetic identity (a + b) mod c = ((a mod c) + (b mod c)) mod c <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[48]</ref>. Assuming the dimensionality of ϵ is sufficiently large and that Lindeberg's condition holds, the Central Limit Theorem (CLT) suggests that a T ℓ ϵ converges to a Gaussian distribution N 0, σ 2 ∆ a ℓ <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[49]</ref>. Consequently, the term ϵ ℓ follows a wrapped Gaussian distribution. To facilitate the approximation of this distribution, we introduce Lemma 2.</p><p>Lemma 2 (Approximation of wrapped Gaussian with vM distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[50]</ref>): Consider a random variable β ∼ N (µ, σ 2 ). Its wrapped version, defined as ω ≜ β (mod 2π), can be approximated by a vM distribution: ψ ∼ vM µ mod 2π, A -1 exp(-σ 2 /2) . Based on Lemma 2, we can approximate ϵ ℓ with a vM distribution vM(0, ρ ∆,ℓ ), where ρ ∆,ℓ = A -1 expσ 2 ∆ a ℓ /2 . We validate this approximation in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_29">13</ref> by plotting the distribution of ϵ ℓ . According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(29)</ref>, where θℓ ∼ vM(µ j , κℓ ) and ϵ ℓ ∼ vM(0, ρ ∆,ℓ ), we apply the convolution approximation from <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[50]</ref>, which yields θℓ ∼ vM µ j , A -1 A(κ ℓ )A(ρ ∆,ℓ ) , thereby completing the proof.</p><p>3) Approximation of expected gradient norm a ℓ : Note that the parameter a ℓ depends on the complex internal weights of f ℓ (•), making it intractable to model explicitly. According to numerous experimental results, we observe that a ℓ can be approximated by an exponential function as <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(15)</ref> (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_30">14</ref> for validation). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Proof of Corollary 1</head><p>We prove the two claims in Proposition 1 as follows.</p><p>1) Monotonicity of (16) w.r.t. J and κ ∆,ℓ : The first part is trivial because the integrand is positive, and the increasing J shrinks the integration interval, which naturally reduces the integral. To prove the second part, we begin by analyzing the integrand defined as f (x, κ) ≜ exp(κ cos x) πI0(κ) . For ∀ 0 &lt; κ 1 &lt; κ 2 , we define g(x) △ = ln f (x, κ 2 )ln f (x, κ 1 ) = (κ 2κ 1 ) cos(x)ln I 0 (κ 2 )ln I 0 (κ 1 ) . Observe that ln I 0 (x) ′ = I1(x) I0(x) = A(x), then we have ln I 0 (κ 2 )ln I 0 (κ 1 ) = A(ξ)(κ 2κ 1 ) for some ξ ∈ (κ 1 , κ 2 ) by Lagrange's Mean Value Theorem. Therefore g(0) = 1 -A(ξ) (κ 2κ 1 ) &gt; 0 since A(x) &lt; 1 for ∀x &gt; 0. And g(π) = -(κ 2κ 1 )ln I 0 (κ 2 )ln I 0 (κ 1 ) &lt; 0 because ln I 0 (x) is a monotonically increasing function. Additionally, g(x) decreases monotonically in (0, π). Hence, there exists a unique x 0 ∈ (0, π) such that g(x 0 ) = 0. Therefore, when 0 &lt; x &lt; x 0 , g(x) &gt; 0 and thus f (x, κ 2 ) &gt; f (x, κ 1 ), and when x 0 &lt; x &lt; π, g(x) &lt; 0 and thus f (x, κ 2 ) &lt; f (x, κ 1 ).</p><p>If x 0 ≥ π J , we have π J 0 f (x, κ 2 ) dx -π J 0 f (x, κ 1 ) dx = π J 0 f (x, κ 2 )f (x, κ 1 ) dx &gt; 0. Otherwise, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_58">π J 0 f (x, κ 2 ) dx - π J 0 f (x, κ 1 ) dx = 1 - π π J f (x, κ 2 ) dx -1 - π π J f (x, κ 1 ) dx = π π J f (x, κ 1 ) -f (x, κ 2 ) dx &gt; 0.<label>(31)</label></formula><p>Since for both situations we have π J 0 f (x, κ 2 ) dxπ J 0 f (x, κ 1 ) dx &gt; 0, we conclude that π J 0 f (x, κ 2 ) dx &gt; π J 0 f (x, κ 1 ) dx for ∀ 0 &lt; κ 1 &lt; κ 2 . This completes the proof. Combining the result about the monotonicity of ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_34">16</ref>) w.r.t. κ ∆,ℓ , the proof is completed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D. Proof of Corollary 2</head><p>The first part is straightforward: as σ 2 ∆ → ∞, we have κ → 0. Given the continuity of P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) with respect to κ ∆,ℓ , substituting κ ∆,ℓ = 0 into (16) completes the proof. For the second part, we observe that as ℓ → ∞, κ ∆,ℓ → ∞. We proceed by establishing the following conclusion:</p><formula xml:id="formula_59">I 0 (κ; a) ≈ e κ √ 2πκ erf a κ 2 , (<label>32</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_60">)</formula><p>where I 0 (κ; a) </p><p>which completes the proof.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E. Proof of Proposition 2</head><p>We first consider the asymptotic analysis of 1 -P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) w.r.t. κ ∆,ℓ .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">-</head><p>I 0 (κ ∆,ℓ ; π J ) I 0 (κ ∆,ℓ ; π) ∼ 1 -</p><formula xml:id="formula_62">erf π J κ ∆,ℓ 2 erf π κ ∆,ℓ 2 (a) ∼ 1 -erf π J κ ∆,ℓ 2 (b) ∼ √ 2 J π 3/2 √ κ exp - π 2 2J 2 κ ∆,ℓ ,<label>(35)</label></formula><p>where (a) holds because the erf π κ 2 saturates quickly and approach 1 when κ is large. (b) holds because of the asymptotic expansion of erf(•) as erf(z) ∼ 1-e -z 2 z √ π <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[51]</ref>. Note that when σ ∆ = 0, we have κ ∆,ℓ = c 1 ℓ + c 2 . Substituting it into (35) yields the stated results.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>11 Fig. 1 :</head><label>111</label><figDesc>Fig. 1: The relationship between inference accuracy, traversal depth, and quantization bit-width. Two settings of bit-width are utilized. The model used is ResNet-152 with intermediate classifiers, and on the dataset CIFAR-10.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>7 5 Y p b d W c g y 8 T L S Q V y 1 P v l r + 4 g Y k m I 0 j B B t e 5 4 b m x 6K V W G M 4 H T U j f R G F M 2 p k P s W C p p i L q X z h J P y Y l V B i S I l H 3 S k J n 6 e y O l o d a T 0 L e T W U K 9 6 G X i f 1 4 n M c F 1 L + U y T g x K N v 8 o S A Q x E c n O J w O u k B k x s Y Q y x W 1 W w k Z U U W Z s S S V b g r d 4 8 j J p n l W 9 y + r F 3 X m l 5 u Z 1 F O E I j u E U P L i C G t x C H R r A Q M I z v MK b o 5 0 X 5 9 3 5 m I 8 W n H z n E P 7 A + f w B / h m R F g = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; z &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " + Z H l C q A S w + 8 s Z 0 O b P x O B x + I k 8 4 w = " &gt; A A A B / H i c b V D L S s N A F J 3 4 r P U V 7 d J N s A i u S i K + l g U 3 L i v Y B z S h T C a T d u h k E m Z u h B j i r 7 h x o Y h b P 8 S d f + O k z U J b D w w c z r m X e + b 4 C W c K b P v b W F l d W 9 / Y r G 3 V t 3 d 2 9 / b N g 8 O e i l N J a J f E P J Y D H y v K m a B d Y M D p I J E U R z 6 n f X 9 6 U / r 9 B y o</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>H p w X 5 9 3 5 m L e u O P n M E f y B 8 / k D 2 X O M 7 Q = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; q &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " o H W + R Z e n 2 t l U a c a H C e q R 0 Q y d Q 5 4 = " &gt; A A A B 6 3 i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 n E r 2 P B i 8 c K 9 g P a U D b b S b t 0 s w m 7 G 6 G E / g U v H h T x 6 h / y 5 r 9 x 0 + a g r Q8 G H u / N M D M v S A T X x n W / n d L a + s b m V n m 7 s r O 7 t 3 9 Q P T x q 6 z h V D F s s F r H q B l S j 4 B J b h h u B 3 U Q h j Q K B n W B y l / u d J 1 S a x / L R T B P 0 I z q S P O S M m l z q o x C D a s 2 t u 3 O Q V e I V p A Y F m o P q V 3 8 Y s z R C a Z i g W v c 8 N z F + R p X h T O C s 0 k 8 1 J p R N 6 Ah 7 l k o a o f a z + a 0 z c m a V I Q l j Z U s a M l d / T 2 Q 0 0 n o a B b Y z o m a s l 7 1 c / M / r p S a 8 9 T M u k 9 S g Z I t F Y S q I i U n + O B l y h c y I q S W U K W 5 v J W x M F W X G x l O x I X j L L 6 + S 9 k X d u 6 5 f P V z W G m 4 R R x l O 4 B T O w Y M b a M A 9 N K E F D M b w D K / w 5 k T O i / P u f C x a S 0 4 x c w x / 4 H z + A A s 8 j j M = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; Result feedback &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " m i h A D N J c N 8 G U E r M 1 T x b Q j z N j 7 r E = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V D L S g M x F L 1 T X 7 W + q i 7 d B I v g q s y I r 2 X B j c s K 9 o F t K Z n 0 T h u a y Q x J R i x D / 8 K N C 0 X c + j f u / B s z 7 S y 0 9 U D g c M 6 9 5 N z j x 4 J r 4 7 r f T m F l d W 1 9 o 7 h Z 2 t r e 2 d 0 r 7 x 8 0</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>X H e n Y 9 F a 8 k p Z o 7 J H z i f P 3 d v k e w = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ŷω</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a t e x i t &gt; z2 Adaptive exit &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 2 1 i 4 i U J o 4 7 N 0 u W s H s 7 s / Y E g j J 6 o = " &gt; A A A B + 3 i c b V D L S s N A F L 3 x W e s r 1 q W b Y B F c S E n E 1 7 I g i A s X F e w D 2 l A m 0 0 k 7 d G Y S Z i Z i C f k V N y 4 U c e u P u PN v n L R Z a O u B g c M 5 9 3 L P n C B m V G n X / b a W l l d W 1 9 Z L G + X N r e 2 d X X u v 0 l J R I j F p 4 o h F s h M g R R g V p K m p Z q Q T S 4 J 4 w E g 7 G F / n f v u R S E U j 8 a A n M f E 5 Gg o a U o y 0 k f p 2 5 a a f 9 j j S I 8 l T L E R 2 c p f 1 7 a p b c 6 d w F o l X k C o U a P T t r 9 4 g w g k n Q m O G l O p 6 b q z 9 F E l N M S N Z u Z c o E i M 8 R k P S N V Q g T p S f T r N n z p F R B k 4 Y S f O E d q b q 7 4 0 U c a U m P D C T e U w 1 7 + X i f 1 4 3 0 e G V n 1 I R J 5 o I P D s U J s z R k Z M X 4 Q y o J F i z i S E I S 2 q y O n i E J M L a 1 F U 2 J X j z X 1 4 k r d O a d 1 E 7 v z + r 1 t 2 i j h I c w C E c g w e X U I d b a E A T M D z B M 7 z C m 5 V Z L 9 a 7 9 T E b X b K K n X 3 4 A + v z B z 6 R l I g = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; F cnn,L &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " E D / Z 6 4 Z Q I + r 7 S L 4 q D</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>&lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; zL … … &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " N t 6 l D 1 W O E Y a C a l E W T Z D l L b e r u 2 I = " &gt; A A A B 8 H i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 B I v g q S T i 1 7 H g x W M F W y t t K J v t p l 2 6 u w m 7 E y G E / g o v H h T x 6 s / x 5 r 9 x 2 + a g r Q 8 G H u / N M D M v T A Q 3 6 H n f T m l l d W 1 9 o 7 x Z 2 d r e 2 d 2 r 7 h + 0 T Z x q y l o 0 F r H u h M Q w w R V r I U f B O o l m R I a C P Y T j m 6 n / 8 M S 0 4 b G 6 x y x h g S R D x S N O C V r p s T c i m G e T v t + v 1 r y 6 N 4 O 7 T P y C 1 K B A s 1 / 9 6 g 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>K b o 5 0 X 5 9 3 5 m L e W n G L m E P 7 A + f w B 2 j u Q Z g = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ŷ1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " y 3 0 M S K y 4 e Q J q n W w k s N 9 g i 2 w L e j Q = " &gt; A A A B 8 H i c b V D L S g N B E O y N r x h f U Y 9 e B o P g K e w G X 8 e A F 4 8 R z E O S J c x O J s m Q m d 1 l p l d Y l n y F F w + K e P V z v P k 3 T p I 9 a G</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>4 s b P 5 g d P y Z l V B m Q Y a V s h k r n 6 e y K j y p h U B b Z T U R y b Z W 8 m / u d 1 E x z e + J k I 4 w R 5 y B a L h o k k G J H Z 9 2 Q g N G c o U 0 s o 0 8 L e S t i Y a s r Q Z l S y I X j L L 6 + S V q 3 q X V U v 7 y 8 q d T e P o w g n c A r n 4 M E 1 1 O E O G t A E B g q e 4 R X e H O 2 8 O O / O x 6 K 1 4 O Q z x / A H z u c P 2 7 + Q Z w = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ŷ2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " V o 0 I V o o t l R I l G 4 1 J o r s B V o k z V Z Y = " &gt; A A A B 8 H i c b V D L S g N B E O y N r x h f U Y 9 e F o P g K e y K r 2 P A i w c P E c x D k i X M T i b J k J n Z Z a Z X W J Z 8 h R c P i n j 1 c 7 z 5 N 0 6 S P W h i Q U N R 1 U 1 3 V x g L b t D z v p 3 C y u r a + k Z x s 7 S 1 v b O 7 V 9 4 / a J o o 0 Z Q 1 a C Q i 3 Q 6 J Y Y I r 1 k C O g r V j z Y g M B W u F 4 5 u p 3 3 p i 2 v B I P W A a s 0 C S o e I D T g l a 6 b E 7 I p i l k 9 5 d r 1 z x q t 4 M 7 j L x c 1 K B H P V e + a v b j 2 g i m U I q i D E d 3 4 s x y I h G T g W b l</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>1 &lt;</head><label>1</label><figDesc>3 u r S E d G E o s 2 o Z E P w F 1 9 e J s 2 z q n 9 Z v b g / r 9 S 8 P I 4 i H M E x n I I P V 1 C D W 6 h D A y h I e I Z X e H O 0 8 + K 8 O x / z 1 o K T z x z C H z i f P w M 2 k I E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ŷL &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 1 2 3 S c T A w A Y C 9 Z y 2 + 9 o U L x o w T P S k = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V D L S g N B E O y N r x h f U Y 9 e B o P g K e y K r 2 N AE I 8 R z Q O S J c x O Z p M h s 7 P L T K 8 Q l n y C F w + K e P W L v P k 3 T p I 9 a G J B Q 1 H V T X d X k E h h 0 H W / n c L K 6 t r 6 R n G z t L W 9s 7 t X 3 j 9 o m j j V j D d Y L G P d D q j h U i j e Q I G S t x P N a R R I 3 g p G N 1 O / 9 c S 1 E b F 6 x H H C / Y g O l A g F o 2 i l h 9 u e 1 y t X 3 K o 7 A 1 k m X k 4 q k K P e K 3 9 1 + z F L I 6 6 Q S W p M x 3 M T 9 D O q U T D J J 6 V u a n h C 2 Y g O e M d S R S N u / G x 2 6 o S c W K V P w l j b U k h m 6 u + J j E b G j K P A d k Y U h 2 b R m 4 r / e Z 0 U w 2 s / E y p J k S s 2 X x S m k m B M p n + T v t C c o R x b Q p k W 9 l b C h l R T h j a d k g 3 B W 3 x 5 m T T P q t 5 l 9 e L + v F J z 8 z i K c A T H c A o e X E E N 7 q A O D W A w g G d 4 h T d H O i / O u / M x b y 0 4 + c w h / I H z + Q O 9 S 4 1 m &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; F l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " I J O l 0 W a J / J K q k d u p T D A e f v v 3 8 k 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h d 3 g 6 x g Q x G N E 8 4 B k C b O T 3 m T I 7 O w y M y</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>2 &lt;</head><label>2</label><figDesc>7 p a 9 u P 2 Z p h N I w Q b X u e G 5 i / I w q w 5 n A S b G b a k w o G 9 E B d i y V N E L t Z 7 N T J + T U K n 0 S x s q W N G S m / p 7 I a K T 1 O A p s Z 0 T N U C 9 6 U / E / r 5 O a 8 N r P u E x S g 5 L N F 4 W p I C Y m 0 7 9 J n y t k R o w t o U x x e y t h Q 6 o o M z a d o g 3 B W 3 x 5 m T S r F e + y c n F / X q 6 5 e R w F O I Y T O A M P r q A G d 1 C H B j A Y w D O 8 w p s j n B f n 3 f m Y t 6 4 4 + c w R / I H z + Q O + z 4 1 n &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; F l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " C A a n 2 d h W E r m f 8 M d L / h B F 6 S D K o l Q = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V D L S g N B E O y N r x h f U Y 9 e B o P g K e y K r 2 N A E A 8 e I p o H J E u Y n f Q m Q 2 Z n l 5 l Z I S z 5 B C 8 e F P H q F 3 n z b 5 w k e 9 B o Q U N R 1 U 1 3 V 5 A I r o 3 r f j m F p e W V 1 b X i e m l j c 2 t 7 p 7 y 7 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Fig. 2 :Fig. 3 :</head><label>23</label><figDesc>Fig. 2: The system model of the channel-adaptive edge inference. The bit-width q and traversal depth ℓ are controlled w.r.t. SNR.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Fig. 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4: The distributions of the 2D and angular features. In the angular domain, the class centroids are distributed evenly and the concentration level across different classes are similar.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>κ ∆,ℓ w.r.t. bit-width.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Fig. 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5: κ ∆,ℓ w.r.t. traversal depth and bit-width.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Fig. 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Fig. 6: Inference accuracy function in (16) w.r.t. the traversal depth, ℓ, and angular-feature distribution parameter, κ ∆,ℓ .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head>Fig. 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Fig. 7: Performance of channel-adaptive AI with CR.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a)  demonstrate the superiority of channel-adaptive</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Fig. 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Fig. 8: Performance of practical channel-adaptive AI.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head>Fig. 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Fig. 9: The theoretical and experimental inference accuracy.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Inference accuracy w.r.t. q.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_25"><head>Fig. 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Fig. 10: The performance of the inference model with different bit-width and traversal depth.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_28"><head>Fig. 11 :Fig. 12 :</head><label>1112</label><figDesc>Fig. 11: The performance of channel-adaptive AI algorithm with different numbers of exit layers. The target accuracy is 90%.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_29"><head>Fig. 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Fig. 13: The distribution of distortion in angular space w.r.t. different traversal depths.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_30"><head>Fig. 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Fig.14: a ℓ and the fitted curve.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_31"><head>2 )</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Monotonicity of (16) w.r.t. σ 2 ∆ and ℓ: Both A(c 1 ℓ + c 2 ) and expσ 2 ∆ c 3 exp(-c 4 ℓ)/2 are positive and increase monotonically w.r.t. ℓ. Hence, their product, denoted as D(σ 2 ∆ , ℓ), increases monotonically w.r.t. ℓ. Additionally, D(σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) decreases monotonically w.r.t. σ 2 ∆ . Therefore, κ ∆,ℓ = A -1 D(σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) decreases monotonically w.r.t. σ 2 ∆ and increases monotonically w.r.t. ℓ.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_32"><head>2 )</head><label>2</label><figDesc>κ cos (x)) dx and erf(x) dθ. Considering Taylor's series for approximation, we have cos(θ) ≈ 1θ 2 /2, and therefore I 0 (κ; a) holds by replacing variable θ with µ κ 2 . Thereby, (32) is proved. Hence,lim κ ∆,ℓ →∞ P (σ 2 ∆ , ℓ) = lim κ ∆,ℓ →∞ I 0 (κ ∆,ℓ ; π J ) I 0 (κ; π)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>z Edge device Edge server IC 2 control SNR Quantizer Dequantizer</head><label></label><figDesc>1 e M a q e B / s D 4 / A E t 2 p U R &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt;</figDesc><table><row><cell>&lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " t s Z u</cell></row><row><cell>Transmission</cell></row><row><cell>over channel</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>TABLE I :</head><label>I</label><figDesc>Different sets of exit layers for implementing channel-adaptive AI.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2"># of exit layers Set of exit layers</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>9, 49</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>9, 39, 49</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>9, 29, 39, 49</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>9, 19, 29, 39, 49</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>We consider an edge inference system where the backbone model ResNet-152 with 50 bottleneck layers is split. The first 11 bottleneck layers are in the edge device, and the remaining L = 39 bottleneck layers are in the edge server. The set of exit layers that supports adaptive exit is: 9, 14, 19, 29, 34, 37. The total bandwidth is B = 100 MHz, and the maximal air latency is T max = 12 ms. The computation speeds of the edge device and the server are set to 0.1 and 0.5 TFLOPS, respectively. The maximal bit-width per feature is Q = 32. EPR and inference accuracy are two metrics to represent the inference performance in the experiments. The former one is analogous to the communication rate, illustrating how efficiently we can process bits in unit inference time. The latter one is obtained by using part of the test dataset to perform the inference process with IID channel realizations and calculating the ratio of correctly classified ones. 2000 IID inference tasks are performed, and the performance is averaged. • Real-world datasets: CIFAR-10 is used in our experiments. It comprises a training dataset with 60, 000 labeled samples and a test set with 10, 000 labeled samples. The data have J = 10 classes. The training dataset is used to train the ResNet-152 model and the accompanying CNNs. The test set is randomly split into two sub-datasets with the ratio of 8 : 2. The first sub-dataset, which we call the validation dataset, is used to estimate the hyperparameters in the channel-adaptive algorithm. And the remaining part, which we call the (final) test dataset, is used to evaluate the inference performance. • Channel-adaptive AI (CA 2 I): Consider the algorithm designed in the preceding section, for which the traversal depth for inference adapts to the channel state according</figDesc><table /><note><p>• System and communication setting: • Metrics:</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>TABLE II :</head><label>II</label><figDesc>Different sets of exit layers for implementing channel-adaptive AI.</figDesc><table><row><cell># of exit layers</cell><cell>Set of exit layers</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>9, 37</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>9, 19, 37</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>9, 19, 29, 37</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>9, 19, 29, 34, 37</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>9, 14, 19, 29, 34, 37</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>J. Zhang, J. Huang, and K. Huang are with the Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong. Emails: jrzhang@eee.hku.hk, jianhaoh@hku.hk and huangkb@eee.hku.hk (Corresponding author: K. Huang).</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_1"><p>Although q is limited to rational values in this context, we still consider it to be continuous.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Communication-Efficient Edge AI: Algorithms and Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuanming</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-1418-7465</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-1360-8141</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-5947-2788</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-5222-1898</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Khaled</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Letaief</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0003-2519-6401</idno>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/comst.2020.3007787</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Communications Surveys &amp; Tutorials</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Commun. Surv. Tutorials</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2373-745X</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2167" to="2191" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrated sensing and edge ai: Realizing intelligent perception in 6g</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Niyato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Commun. Surv. Tutor</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Green edge ai: A contemporary survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Mao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. IEEE</title>
		<meeting>IEEE</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Edge Intelligence: Paving the Last Mile of Artificial Intelligence With Edge Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhi</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-0987-9344</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xu</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0001-9943-6020</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">En</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-9928-5813</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liekang</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0003-4800-8768</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ke</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0003-0118-7236</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Junshan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-3840-1753</idno>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/jproc.2019.2918951</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Proc. IEEE</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0018-9219</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1558-2256</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1738" to="1762" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-08">2019</date>
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Parametric-sensitivity aware retransmission for efficient ai downloading</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2602.13607</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2026">2026</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Communication-Computation Trade-off in Resource-Constrained Edge Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jiawei</forename><surname>Shao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/mcom.001.2000373</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Communications Magazine</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Commun. Mag.</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0163-6804</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1558-1896</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-12">2020</date>
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taskoriented sensing, computation, and communication integration for multidevice edge ai</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Eldar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2486" to="2502" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward an intelligent edge: Wireless communication meets machine learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>You</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Commun. Mag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variable-rate variable-power mqam for fading channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goldsmith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S.-G</forename><surname>Chua</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1218" to="1230" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive coded modulation for fading channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goldsmith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S.-G</forename><surname>Chua</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="595" to="602" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Energy-efficient edge inference in integrated sensing, communication, and computation networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint device scheduling and resource allocation for iscc-based multi-view-multi-task inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Internet of Things Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Partialloading: User scheduling and bandwidth allocation for parameter-sharing edge inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Qu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2503.22982</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Progressive feature transmission for split classification at the wireless edge</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Lan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Popovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gündüz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3837" to="3852" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine learning at the wireless edge: Distributed stochastic gradient descent over-the-air</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Amiri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gündüz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2155" to="2169" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Federated learning via overthe-air computation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. on Wireless Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2022" to="2035" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimized power control for over-the-air computation in fading channels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7498" to="7513" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal model placement and online model splitting for device-edge co-inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8354" to="8367" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Communication efficient cooperative edge ai via event-triggered computation offloading</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>You</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2501.02001</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wireless channel adaptive dnn split inference for resource-constrained edge devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Communications Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1520" to="1524" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adaptive layer splitting for wireless llm inference in edge computing: A model-based reinforcement learning approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2406.02616</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bottlenet++: An end-to-end approach for feature compression in device-edge co-inference systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2020 IEEE International Conference on Communications Workshops (ICC Workshops)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal ai model splitting and resource allocation for device-edge co-inference in multi-user wireless sensing systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic neural networks: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7436" to="7456" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resource allocation for multiuser edge inference with batching and early exiting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Lan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1186" to="1200" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Edge ai: On-demand accelerating deep neural network inference via edge computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="447" to="457" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dual dynamic inference: Enabling more efficient, adaptive, and controllable deep inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T.-K</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Baraniuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Signal Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="623" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Branchynet: Fast inference via early exiting from deep neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Teerapittayanon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mcdanel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H.-T</forename><surname>Kung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2016 23rd international conference on pattern recognition (ICPR)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2464" to="2469" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resource-constrained edge ai with early exit prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Mao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Commun. Inf. Netw</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive neural networks for efficient inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bolukbasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Dekel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Saligrama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>PMLR</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="527" to="536" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep residual learning for image recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. IEEE Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit</title>
		<meeting>IEEE Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="770" to="778" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep learning and the information bottleneck principle</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Tishby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Zaslavsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2015 IEEE Information Theory Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive inference through early-exit networks: Design, challenges and directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Laskaridis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kouris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 5th Int. Wkshps on Embedded and Mobile Deep Learning</title>
		<meeting>5th Int. Wkshps on Embedded and Mobile Deep Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Ahlfors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Ahlfors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Complex analysis</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1979">1979</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning representations by back-propagating errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rumelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">323</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6088</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="533" to="536" />
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gersho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE communications society magazine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="1977">1977</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mathematical theory of communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Shannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Bell system technical journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="423" />
			<date type="published" when="1948">1948</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cosface: Large margin cosine loss for deep face recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. IEEE Comput. Soc. Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit</title>
		<meeting>IEEE Comput. Soc. Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5265" to="5274" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discriminative feature learning approach for deep face recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Qiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European conference on computer vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="515" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">von mises-fisher loss: An exploration of embedding geometries for supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gallagher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mozer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Comput. Vis</title>
		<meeting>IEEE Int. Conf. Comput. Vis</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10612" to="10622" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">von mises-fisher mixture model-based deep learning: Application to face verification</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hasnat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bohné</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Milgram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gentric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1706.04264</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Directional statistics-based deep metric learning for image classification and retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pattern Recognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledge-based ultra-low-latency semantic communications for robotic edge intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The elements of statistical learning: data mining, inference, and prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hastie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Tibshirani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Neuhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2325" to="2383" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to linear regression analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Peck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Vining</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biased and unbiased estimation of the circular mean resultant length and its variance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kutil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="549" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L.-K</forename><surname>Hua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Introduction to number theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Science &amp; Business Media</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Durrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Probability: theory and examples</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge university press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Directional Statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kanti</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Mardia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Jupp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9780470316979</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Directional statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Handbook of mathematical functions, national bureau of standards</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abramowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Mathematics Series</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">55</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1964">1964</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
